<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>code berry | CodeBerry Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/en/tag/code-berry-en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog</link>
	<description>Learn programming online</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 20:25:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Which Programming Language is Right for You?</title>
		<link>/blog/en/which-programming-language-is-right-for-you/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blog-admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 10:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Basics of Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best code language to learn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best coding language for games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best programming language for games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[code berry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CodeBerry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[game development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[most useful programming language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[most useful programming language to learn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the most beautiful programming language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[what code language should i learn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[what coding language should i learn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[what programming language should i learn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[what programming language should i learn for artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[which coding language should i learn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[which programming language should i learn]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://codeberryschool.com/blog/?p=6933</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In CodeBerry Programming School’s “Basics of Programming” series, we discuss programming-related topics and everything you need to know to get started. Stay tuned for new articles and find the answer to every “what”, “why”, and “how”, you may have had about coding! Would you like to learn how to code, online? Come and try our [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b>In CodeBerry Programming School’s “Basics of Programming” </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">series, we discuss programming-related topics and everything you need to know to get started. Stay tuned for new articles and find the answer to every “what”, “why”, and “how”, you may have had about coding!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Would you like to learn how to code, online? Come and <a href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">try our first 25 lessons for free</a> at the CodeBerry Programming School.</span></p>
<h3>Basics of Programming</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/basics-of-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Basics of Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/a-brief-introduction-to-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">A Brief Introduction to Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/why-you-should-learn-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Why You Should Learn Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-much-can-you-make-as-a-programmer/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How much can you make as a programmer?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How to learn to code?</a></li>
<li><strong>Which programming language is good for you?</strong></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-long-it-takes-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How Long It Takes to Learn to Code</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/choosing-beginner-programming-course/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How to find the right beginner programming course for you?</a></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You’ve read the articles, searched the web, and done all the research you can on programming. Now, it’s time to finally make the big decision: “what programming language should I learn?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Great question. Fortunately for you, we have a step-by-step guide that will help you decide what your motivation is for learning to code and which programming languages you should then learn.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12123 alignright" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/1-683x1024.png" alt="" width="304" height="456" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/1-683x1024.png 683w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/1-200x300.png 200w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/1-768x1152.png 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/1.png 800w" sizes="(max-width: 304px) 100vw, 304px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even if you’re still in the searching stage, this guide should give you some clarity regarding the purpose of the most common programming languages and your preferred niche. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’ve also identified four distinct ways to rank the top programming languages: by </span><b>popularity</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><b>ease-of-learning, earning potential</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and </span><b>usefulness</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Disclaimer: In this article, we’ve grouped markup languages, such as HTML and CSS, and scripting languages, such as Bash/Shell and SQL, into the category of programming languages.</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let’s start with a list of the top ten most popular programming languages according to <a href="https://insights.stackoverflow.com/survey/2018/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">StackOverflow</a>:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In this list, we see JavaScript, HTML, and CSS taking the top 3 spots for the most popular programming languages. These three languages are the backbone of front-end web development and serve as a great starting point for beginners. SQL is used for database management and the rest, such as Java, Python, C#, PHP, and C++, are general-purpose languages that you can use for a variety of tasks. Bash/Shell, on the other hand, is a command language used to communicate with Unix-based operating systems, like Linux and macOS.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12017 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What about the easiest languages to learn? </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12124 alignleft" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/3-683x1024.png" alt="" width="300" height="450" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/3-683x1024.png 683w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/3-200x300.png 200w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/3-768x1152.png 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/3.png 800w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fortunately, many of the most popular programming languages are also the easiest to learn. However, we also find some more obscure programming languages, such as R and Erlang. R is a coding language designed for statistical computing and mathematics and is a great tool for data analysis (which we’ll discuss later in the article). Erlang is primarily used for telecommunication and is present in many messaging applications, such as WhatsApp.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8230;and the top-paying programming languages? </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12125 alignright" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/5-683x1024.png" alt="" width="314" height="471" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/5-683x1024.png 683w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/5-200x300.png 200w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/5-768x1152.png 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/5.png 800w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re new to programming, you probably didn’t recognize many of the languages on this list. Since computer programming is a rapidly evolving industry, the highest-paid skills tend to be related to the newest, most cutting edge technologies. However, knowledge of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript is enough to get you started in your career—other languages can wait. </span></p>
<h2><b>Overview</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Besides salary, popularity, and ease of learning, you probably have your own personal motivations to learn a specific programming language. In the area below, we’ll examine some of the determining factors that might help you decide on a programming language and what uses they have. </span></p>
<h2><b>Choosing a Language by Usefulness</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is where things get a bit more complicated. How “useful” a language is to you will depend on what you’d like to accomplish with code. For example, HTML and CSS might be extremely useful to a front-end web developer, while Swift and Java are more useful to a mobile developer. Some programming languages, like Python, are designed for general purpose use, but many others are specialized tools that will help you complete specific tasks. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">First, let’s determine why you want to learn to code, decide what area you’d like to focus on, and then find the programming language that is right for you:</span></p>
<h2><b>I Want to Be a Professional Developer</b></h2>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Game Developer</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re passionate about becoming a game developer, there are two main programming languages that you’ll have to master: C++ and C#. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’d like to develop fun, 2D mobile games that are based on community and online interaction, C# is definitely the choice for you. C# is easier to learn and less complicated than C++, making it the main programming language of indie and mobile games. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">C++, on the other hand, delivers incredible power and can be used for 3D mobile games and “AAA” titles for PC and console. To create video games with the best performance and the most beautiful graphics, C++ is the way to go. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Web Developer</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In our article, “<a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/a-brief-introduction-to-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">A Brief Introduction to Programming</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">”</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, we talked a lot about the big three programming languages for web development: HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. HTML handles the format, CSS determines the style, and JavaScript makes the page come alive. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For web developers who focus primarily on UX (user experience), HTML5 and JavaScript are their most commonly used tools. Web developers involved in e-commerce, however, shift their focus to more advanced languages, such as Java, Ruby, Python, PHP, and C#. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Web programmers for small businesses will probably use PHP, while programmers for recent startups use Java, Ruby, and JavaScript for most of their work. Enterprise web developers tend to use C# and Java more often for bigger, Windows-based applications. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mobile Developer</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mobile development is a bit more straightforward and only requires you to know one programming language per operating system. </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6957" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/rami-al-zayat-170349-unsplash-1.jpg" alt="" width="5184" height="3456" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/rami-al-zayat-170349-unsplash-1.jpg 5184w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/rami-al-zayat-170349-unsplash-1-300x200.jpg 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/rami-al-zayat-170349-unsplash-1-768x512.jpg 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/rami-al-zayat-170349-unsplash-1-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/rami-al-zayat-170349-unsplash-1-1080x720.jpg 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 5184px) 100vw, 5184px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you want to create mobile apps for the iPhone or iPad, all you need to know is Swift, Apple’s own programming language for iOS. Introduced in 2014, Swift is a very powerful language that was designed to allow you to program nearly any Apple device. With knowledge of Swift, you can also write applications for Mac, the Apple Watch, and Apple TV!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mobile development for Android has taken off in recent years and has grown to surpass the popularity of development for iOS. Android is based on Java, making it super easy to learn if you already have experience using the language. You can also go from developing apps for Android to doing a ton of other cool things after you’ve gained the experience in Java. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last, but not least, we come to the Windows phone. The Windows mobile OS runs on C#, one of Microsoft’s very own programming languages. Coding in C# is an extremely valuable skill that any Windows developer should know. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, we are seeing the lines begin to blur as both mobile and desktop become more unified. Rather than being separated by mobile and desktop, programming languages are instead segregated by the ecosystem (Microsoft, Google, and Apple). Google even developed their own language called “Go”, which we might see in the future as a replacement for Java in Android. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Desktop Software</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As we mentioned above, the same programming languages that you’ll need for mobile development can be used to develop desktop software as well. If you’re interested in developing software for Windows platforms, you’ll want to learn C#. To develop cross-platform software and programs for Mac, you should learn Java and Swift, respectively. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are also several strong, web-based solutions for developing cross-platform desktop software with just HTML, CSS and JavaScript, such as </span><a href="https://electronjs.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Electron</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12028 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-2.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-2-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-2-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data Science</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the field of data science, Python and R are the most useful languages you can learn. Python is like a swiss army knife of programming languages that were designed for general purpose use. However, the strength of Python comes from the vast wealth of free data analysis libraries that are packed full of capabilities. One of the most popular data analysis libraries, Pandas, comes with tools that allow you to import information from spreadsheets or processing sets for time-series analysis. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">R is another programming language that is geared towards statistical analysis and graphing. With R, you can include </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">linear and nonlinear modeling, classical statistical tests, time-series analysis, classification, clustering, and more.</span></p>
<h2><b>I Want to Run a Startup</b></h2>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Web</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Web-based startups have a lot of options when it comes to choosing a programming language. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For e-commerce startups, PHP is a great language to start with. WordPress runs on PHP and is a great starting platform for e-commerce websites.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you want to start a SaaS (Software as a Service) startup, Java is a necessary language to learn. With Java, you’ll be able to develop software for a huge variety of platforms, from Android to Windows.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thanks to the Ruby on Rails framework, Ruby is a powerful, easy-to-use language that makes prototyping a breeze. As a high-level language, you’ll be able to create prototypes quickly and bring your idea to life with minimal effort.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Finally, we have JavaScript which directly affects the overall performance of your website. Since your startup is web-based, the performance and user experience is extremely important. These days, search engines like Google will punish you and lower your search results rankings for a slow loading and laggy site. This can make a huge impact on the number of visitors and conversions you receive.</span></p>
<h2><b>I Want to Run a Startup (Version 2.0) </b></h2>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Web</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since the storefront of an online shop is a website, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript will be necessary for the front-end. However, you do have plenty of options for the back-end, which accounts for all of the “behind-the-scenes” operations of your online store. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For handling the back-end, you’ll most likely use Node.js (JavaScript), Ruby, or PHP. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Of the three, Node.js is the most popular and widely used, both because of its speed and its basis in JavaScript. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since your startup is web-based, the performance and user experience is extremely important. These days, search engines like Google will punish you and lower your search results rankings for a slow loading and laggy site. This can make a huge impact on the amount of visitors and conversions you receive. Therefore, we would recommend the fastest option, Node.js, for the back end. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In extreme cases, you may need to learn Python or R for the back end of your site, but only if you’re dealing with huge amounts of customer or product data. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’d like an easier solution that’s already set up for you, try building your e-commerce shop in WordPress, a PHP-based solution. With WordPress, you can use a drag-and-drop interface to construct the façade of your store, while the program takes care of the front end and back end. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although WordPress is relatively easy to use, you’ll still want to learn the language or hire a PHP developer to add any additional features or troubleshoot problems as they arise. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mobile</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mobile-based startups like Uber are quite popular and successful at the moment. To launch a startup in the mobile space, it’s important that you create apps that are available on both iPhone and Android. It’s actually possible to develop cross-platform applications in Java using React Native, Ionic, PhoneGap, or Cordova, but it’s recommended that you learn the native programming languages for each platform for the best performance.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re not able to code it all yourself, hiring a mobile developer that specializes in a specific operating system can be helpful. You’ll need to hire a Java developer for Android, a Swift developer for iOS, a rare talent that may know both, or opt for a cross-platform solution. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Game</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a startup, you likely won’t have the money and resources to develop ‘AAA’ titles like the big studios. Instead, indie developers tend to focus on storyline and creativity when developing games. C++ is complicated, takes time, and is often difficult to use, meaning that it’s not your best choice as a startup. C# is easier to use and will allow you to release games more quickly and on time. </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6956" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/gaming-1.jpg" alt="" width="4928" height="3264" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/gaming-1.jpg 4928w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/gaming-1-300x199.jpg 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/gaming-1-768x509.jpg 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/gaming-1-1024x678.jpg 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/gaming-1-1080x715.jpg 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 4928px) 100vw, 4928px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Web-based games are another great place to start for new game developers. Through HTML5 and JavaScript, you can create incredible games. To find out what kind of games you can develop with HTML5 and JavaScript, check out this article: </span><a href="https://tutorialzine.com/2015/02/30-amazing-games-made-only-with-html5" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://tutorialzine.com/2015/02/30-amazing-games-made-only-with-html5</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, if you have the patience, skills, and dedication to create an amazing 3D game, you should learn C++. This powerful programming language from Microsoft is just about all you need to create stunning games for console and PC. </span></p>
<h2><b>I Want to Build Something Fun</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The most appealing aspect of programming is not only that it’s useful and highly paid, but also that it can be a lot of fun. If you want to create something cool with coding, you should first consider what kinds of projects interest you. Would you like to create a new mobile app, a web-based game, or even your own AI? Perhaps, you’d like to automate your daily tasks at work or create something for Google Apps (G-Suite)? With a good understanding of the following languages, your imagination will be the only limit to what you can create. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Small Games</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Don’t think you need to be a professional programmer to begin following your dream as a game developer; all you need to know is HTML5, JavaScript, and some WebGL. Both Doodle Jump and the incredibly famous (or infamous) mobile game, Flappy Bird, are powered by HTML5 and JavaScript. Sure, you won’t be making ‘AAA’ games for consoles any time soon, but you’ll be surprised by what you can create with limited knowledge of coding. For slightly more advanced games on desktop, you’ll want to utilize languages like C# and Python. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Google Apps (G-Suite)</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">JavaScript is the backbone for creating apps within the Google ecosystem, or the G-Suite, as it is commonly referred to. Google claims that any web apps in the G-Suite can be created with JavaScript and nothing more. This is a bit of an odd claim, considering that Gmail is actually written in Java, not JavaScript. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Regardless, learning</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> JavaScript is not necessary to create apps in G-Suite anymore. Instead, the new Google App Maker gives you a drag-and-drop interface that allows you to create custom applications and provides you with APIs for all of Google’s applications, such as Google Maps and Google Translate. The API, or Application Program Interface, is the key that enables the communication between other Google apps and your own custom app. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Task Automation</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Have you ever spent countless hours updating a spreadsheet, renaming files, or reorganizing items with your keyboard and mouse? During that mind-numbing experience, did you ever stop to think that there might be a better way? Task Automation is an entire field of programming that is dedicated to automating the boring, mindless tasks that a human would rather not do. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Using basic general-purpose languages like Python and Ruby, you can tell your computer to do all of the grunt work for you. Beyond saving time and stress, automating daily tasks will result in more accurate work, since we tend to make mistakes as we get tired, distracted, and bored. Computers, on the other hand, put their heads down and get the work done without fail.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12019 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-2.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-2-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-2-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Simple AI (Artificial Intelligence)</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In recent years, Python has become increasingly popular in the field of Artificial Intelligence. One of the greatest challenges for software developers of AI is the problem of “deep learning”, which is the ability to learn as a human does. Today, “neural mapping” is a widely-used technique in AI that involves creating large decision-making branches. Each connection is treated as if it were a neuron and a synapse in the brain. Using this technique, researchers in AI hope to create a replica of the brain that reasons and even has the creative capacities like that of a human.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">TensorFlow is a great library of resources for Python and other programming languages. While it was primarily developed for use with Python, TensorFlow.js has been released for JavaScript with the intention of using machine learning on the web. In other words, you can even use JavaScript to experiment with AI through the use of TensorFlow. </span></p>
<h2><b>Conclusion </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We hope that you enjoyed our article and now have a clearer idea of which programming language is right for you. Languages like HTML, CSS, and JavaScript are the best languages to start with, but you definitely can’t go wrong with a great, multi-purpose language like Python and C#.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Please let us know in the comments which programming languages you are currently learning and what motivated you to learn them. See you in the next article!</span></p>
<p><b>In CodeBerry Programming School’s “Basics of Programming” </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">series, we discuss programming-related topics and everything you need to know to get started. Stay tuned for new articles and find the answer to every “what”, “why”, and “how”, you may have had about coding!</span></p>
<h3>Basics of Programming</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/basics-of-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Basics of Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/a-brief-introduction-to-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">A Brief Introduction to Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/why-you-should-learn-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Why You Should Learn Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-much-can-you-make-as-a-programmer/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How much can you make as a programmer?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How to learn to code?</a></li>
<li><strong>Which programming language is good for you?</strong></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-long-it-takes-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How Long It Takes to Learn to Code</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/choosing-beginner-programming-course/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How to find the right beginner programming course for you?</a></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Would you like to learn how to code, online? Come and <a href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">try our first 25 lessons for free</a> at the CodeBerry Programming School.</span></p>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<h2></h2>
<h2 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ef5350;"><strong>Learn to code and change your career!</strong></span></h2>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 40px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12065" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>100% ONLINE</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12066" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-440x440.png 440w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4.png 512w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>IDEAL FOR BEGINNERS</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12067" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SUPPORTIVE COMMUNITY</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12068" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SELF-PACED LEARNING</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 10px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<h3 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #20c997;">Not sure if programming is for you? With CodeBerry you’ll like it.</span></h3>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 30px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-buttons aligncenter">
<div class="wp-block-button is-style-fill"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-white-color has-text-color has-background" style="border-radius: 10px; background-color: #ef5350;" href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><strong>TRY THE FIRST LESSONS FOR FREE</strong></a></div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 25px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12074" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png" sizes="(max-width: 282px) 100vw, 282px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png 564w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1-300x47.png 300w" alt="" width="282" height="45" /></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Things I Wish Someone Had Told Me When I Was Learning How to Code &#8211; And what I’ve learned from teaching others</title>
		<link>/blog/en/things-i-wish-someone-had-told-me-when-i-was-learning-how-to-code/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blog-admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 10:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips and tricks for beginner programmers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Article]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Budapest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[C++]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[code berry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CodeBerry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CodeBerry Programming School]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Good to read]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HTML]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming classes near me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[someone had told]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[things wish someone had told]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://codeberryschool.com/blog/?p=6554</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you need more tricks or advices, check out the following articles too &#8211; in these we are writing about our own experiences and ideas that might can help you to get really good chances at a job interview or earn some more additional skills to improve your programming knowledge! Interview tips that will give [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you need more tricks or advices, check out the following articles too &#8211; in these we are writing about our own experiences and ideas that might can help you to get really good chances at a job interview or earn some more additional skills to improve your programming knowledge!</p>
<ul>
<li class="entry-title"><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/interview-tips-that-will-give-you-confidence-and-help-you-land-a-dev-job/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Interview tips that will give you confidence and help you land a dev job</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/category/basics-of-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Basics of programming</a></li>
</ul>
<h3><b>Before you learn to code, think about what you want to code</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Knowing how to code is mostly about building things, and the path is a lot clearer when you have a sense of the end goal. If your goal is “learn to code,” without a clear idea of the kinds of programs you will write and how they will make your life better, you will probably find it a frustrating exercise.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m a little ashamed to admit that part of my motivation for studying computer science was that I wanted to prove I was smart, and I wanted to be able to get Smart Person jobs. I also liked thinking about math and theory (</span><a href="http://www.amazon.ca/Godel-Escher-Bach-Eternal-Golden/dp/0465026567" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">this book</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> blew my mind at an impressionable age) and the program was a good fit. It wasn’t enough to sustain me for long, though, until I found ways to connect technology to the things I really loved, like music and literature.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12254 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, what do you want to code? Websites? Games? iPhone apps? A startup that makes you rich? Interactive art? Do you want to be able to impress your boss or automate a tedious task so you can spend more time looking at otter pictures? Perhaps you simply want to be more employable, add a buzzword to your resume, or fulfill the requirements of your educational program. All of these are worthy goals. Make sure you know which one is yours, and study accordingly.</span></p>
<h3><b>There’s nothing mystical about it</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Coding is a skill like any other. Like language learning, there’s grammar and vocabulary to acquire. Like math, there are processes to work through specific types of problems. Like all kinds of craftsmanship and art-making, there are techniques and tools and best practices that people have developed over time, specialized to different tasks, that you’re free to use or modify or discard.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.joelonsoftware.com/articles/ThePerilsofJavaSchools.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">This guy</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (a very smart guy! Whose other writings I enjoy and frequently agree with!) posits that there is a bright line between people with the True Mind of a Programmer and everyone else, who are lacking the intellectual capacity needed to succeed in the field. That bright line consists, according to him, of pointers and recursion (there are primers </span><a href="http://alumni.cs.ucr.edu/~pdiloren/C++_Pointers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="http://inventwithpython.com/blog/2011/08/11/recursion-explained-with-the-flood-fill-algorithm-and-zombies-and-cats/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for the curious).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I learned about pointers and recursion in school, and when I understood them, it was a delightful jolt to my brain — the kind of intellectual pleasure that made me want to study computer science in the first place. But, outside of classroom exercises, the number of times I’ve had to be familiar with either concept to get things done has been relatively small. And when helping others learn, over and over again, I’ve watched people complete interesting and rewarding projects without knowing anything about either one.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There’s no point in being intimidated or wondering if you’re Smart Enough. Sure, the more complex and esoteric your task, the higher the level of mastery you will need to complete it. But this is true in absolutely every other field. Unless you’re planning to make your living entirely by your code, chances are you don’t have to be a recursion-understanding genius to make the thing you want to make.</span></p>
<h3><b>It never works the first time</b></h3>
<h4><b>And probably won’t the second or third time</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When you first start learning to code, you’ll very quickly run up against this particular experience: you think you’ve set up everything the way you’re supposed to, you’ve checked and re-checked it, and it still. doesn’t. work. You don’t have a clue where to begin trying to fix it, and the error message (if you’re lucky enough to have one at all) might as well say “fuck you.” You might be tempted to give up at this point, thinking that you’ll never figure it out, that you’re not cut out for this. I had that feeling the first time I tried to write a program in C++, ran it, and got only the words “segmentation fault” for my trouble.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But this experience is so common for programmers of all skill levels that it says absolutely nothing about your intelligence, tech-savviness, or suitability for the coding life. It will happen to you as a beginner, but it will also happen to you as an experienced programmer. The main difference will be in how you respond to it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve found that a big difference between new coders and experienced coders is faith: faith that things are going wrong for a logical and discoverable reason, faith that problems are fixable, faith that there is a way to accomplish the goal. The path from “not working” to “working” might not be obvious, but with patience you can usually find it.</span></p>
<h3><b>Someone will always tell you you’re doing it wrong</b></h3>
<p><a href="http://theprofoundprogrammer.com/page/17" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Braces should go on the next line</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><a href="http://programmers.stackexchange.com/a/2782" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Braces should go on the same line</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><a href="http://derkarl.org/why_to_tabs.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use tabs to indent</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><a href="http://www.emacswiki.org/emacs/TabsAreEvil" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">But tabs are evil</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. You should </span><a href="http://mysqlstoredprocedure.com/index.php?option=com_content&amp;view=article&amp;id=51&amp;Itemid=40" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">use stored procedures</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, but actually </span><a href="http://www.tonymarston.co.uk/php-mysql/stored-procedures-are-evil.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">you shouldn’t use them</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. You should </span><a href="http://www.lanoie.net/classes/DHTML/programming/lectures/lecture.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">always comment your code</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. But </span><a href="http://visualstudiomagazine.com/articles/2013/06/01/roc-rocks.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">good code doesn’t need comments</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are almost always many different approaches to a particular problem, with no single “right way.” A lot of programmers get very good at advocating for their preferred way, but that doesn’t mean it’s the One True Path. Going head-to-head with people telling me I was Wrong, and trying to figure out if they were right, was one of the more stressful aspects of my early career.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re coding in a team with other people, someone will almost certainly take issue with something that you’re doing. Sometimes they’ll be absolutely correct, and it’s always worth investigating to see whether you are, in fact, Doing It Wrong. But sometimes they will be full of shit or re-enacting an ancient and meaningless dispute where it would be best to just follow a style guide and forget about it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the other hand, if you’re the kind of person who enjoys ancient but meaningless disputes (grammar nerds, I’m looking at you), you’ve come to the right place.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12018 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h3><b>Someone will always tell you you’re not a real coder</b></h3>
<p><a href="http://www.cs.tut.fi/~jkorpela/prog.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">HTML isn’t real coding</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><a href="http://the-shaolin.blogspot.ca/2007/12/why-vi-only-true-programmers-editor.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you don’t use vi, you’re not really serious</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><a href="http://www.ericsink.com/entries/c_morse_code.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Real programmers know C</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><a href="http://www.zazzle.ca/real_coders_dont_do_windows_tees-235789605999466863" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Real coders don’t do Windows.</span></a> <a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2006/07/separating-programming-sheep-from-non-programming-goats.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some people will never be able to learn it</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2012/05/please-dont-learn-to-code.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">You shouldn’t learn to code</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><a href="http://fullcomment.nationalpost.com/2013/08/21/chase-felker-youre-not-a-computer-programmer-and-thats-ok/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">You’re not a computer programmer (but I am)</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Coding” means a lot of different things to a lot of different people, and it looks different now from how it used to. And, funnily enough, the tools and packages and frameworks that make it faster and easier for newcomers or even trained developers to build things are most likely to be tarred with the “not for REAL coders” brush. (See: “</span><a href="http://blog.enfranchisedmind.com/2009/04/return-of-the-real-programmer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Return of the Real Programmer</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">”)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Behind all this is the fear that </span><a href="http://fullcomment.nationalpost.com/2013/08/21/chase-felker-youre-not-a-computer-programmer-and-thats-ok/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">if “anyone” can call themselves a programmer, the title will become meaningless</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. But I think that this gatekeeping is destructive.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use the tools that make it easiest to build the things you want to build. If that means your game was made in Stencyl or GameMaker rather than written from scratch, that’s fine. If your first foray into coding is HTML or Excel macros, that’s fine. Work with something you feel you can stick with.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As you get more comfortable, you’ll naturally start to find those tools limiting rather than helpful and look for more powerful ones. But most of the time, few people will ever even look at your code or even ask what you used — It’s what you make with it that counts.</span></p>
<h3><b>Worrying about “geek cred” will slowly kill you</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">See above. I used to worry a lot, especially in school, about whether I was identifying myself as “not a real geek” (and therefore less worthy of inclusion in tech communities) through my clothing, my presentation, my choice of reading material and even my software customization choices. It was a terrible waste of energy and I became a lot more functional after I made the decision to let it all go.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You need to internalize this: your ability to get good at coding has </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">nothing</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to do with how well you fit into the various geek subcultures. This goes double if you know deep down that you’ll never quite fit. The energy you spend proving yourself should be going into making things instead. And, if you’re an indisputable geek with cred leaking from your eye sockets, keep this in mind for when you’re evaluating someone else’s cred level. It may not mean what you think it does.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-7777 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/business-3560932_1920-3.jpg" alt="With a few advice i'ts always easier to learn, how to code" width="1920" height="1280" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/business-3560932_1920-3.jpg 1920w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/business-3560932_1920-3-300x200.jpg 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/business-3560932_1920-3-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/business-3560932_1920-3-768x512.jpg 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/business-3560932_1920-3-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/business-3560932_1920-3-1080x720.jpg 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></p>
<h3><b>Sticking with it is more important than the method</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There’s no shortage of articles about the “right” or “best” way to learn how to code, and there are lots of potential approaches. You can learn the concepts </span><a href="http://pine.fm/LearnToProgram/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">from a book</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or by </span><a href="http://www.codecademy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">completing interactive exercises</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or by </span><a href="http://learnpythonthehardway.org/book/intro.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">debugging things that others have written</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. And, of course, there are lots of languages you might choose as your first to learn, with advocates for each.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A common complaint with “teach yourself to code” programs and workshops is that you’ll breeze happily through the beginner material and then hit a steep curve where things get more difficult very quickly. You know how to print some lines of text on a page but have no idea where to start working on a “real,” useful project. You might feel like you were just following directions without really understanding and blame the learning materials.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12255 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When you get to this stage, most of the tutorials and online resources available to you are much less useful because they assume you’re already an experienced and comfortable programmer. The difficulty is further compounded by the fact that “you don’t know what you don’t know.” Even trying to figure out what to learn next is a puzzle in itself.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You’ll hit this wall no matter what “learn to code” program you follow, and the only way to get past it is to persevere. This means you keep trying new things, learning more information, and figuring out, piece by piece, how to build your project. You’re a lot more likely to find success in the end if you have a clear idea of why you’re learning to code in the first place.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you keep putting bricks on top of each other, it might take a long time but eventually, you’ll have a wall. This is where that faith I mentioned earlier comes in handy. If you believe that with time and patience you can figure the whole coding thing out, in time you almost certainly will. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can find the original English article <a href="https://medium.freecodecamp.org/things-i-wish-someone-had-told-me-when-i-was-learning-how-to-code-565fc9dcb329" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">here</a>.</span></p>
<ul>
<li>If you need more tricks or advice, check out the following articles too – in these, we are writing about our own experiences and ideas that might help you to get really good chances at a job interview or earn some more additional skills to improve your programming knowledge!
<ul>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/interview-tips-that-will-give-you-confidence-and-help-you-land-a-dev-job/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Interview tips that will give you confidence and help you land a dev job</a></li>
<li class="entry-title"><strong>Things I Wish Someone Had Told Me When I Was Learning How to Code</strong></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/category/basics-of-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Basics of programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/basics-of-seo-beginner/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">SEO Basics &#8211; The structure of a healthy website</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/software-developer-software-engineer/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Is there a difference between programmer and developer?</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<h2></h2>
<h2 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ef5350;"><strong>Learn to code and change your career!</strong></span></h2>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 40px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12065" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>100% ONLINE</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12066" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-440x440.png 440w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4.png 512w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>IDEAL FOR BEGINNERS</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12067" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SUPPORTIVE COMMUNITY</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12068" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SELF-PACED LEARNING</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 10px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<h3 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #20c997;">Not sure if programming is for you? With CodeBerry you’ll like it.</span></h3>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 30px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-buttons aligncenter">
<div class="wp-block-button is-style-fill"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-white-color has-text-color has-background" style="border-radius: 10px; background-color: #ef5350;" href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><strong>TRY THE FIRST LESSONS FOR FREE</strong></a></div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 25px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12074" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png" sizes="(max-width: 282px) 100vw, 282px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png 564w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1-300x47.png 300w" alt="" width="282" height="45" /></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>I&#8217;m Adam Freisinger, the founder of CodeBerry, and this is how I work</title>
		<link>/blog/en/adam-freisinger-founder-of-codeberry/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blog-admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 08:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meet the CodeBerry team]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adam Freisinger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BASIC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Budapest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[code berry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[code founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CodeBerry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[codeberry school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[founder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to learn to code]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hungary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learn to code]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming classes near me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web developing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://codeberryschool.com/?p=5215</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Adam Freisinger finished his studies as a Pharmacist and Health Care Manager, but ended up working as a web developer. Since then he has founded two IT companies. One of them being CodeBerry, a programming school that teaches web development online in english. Tune in to read more about adventure games written in BASIC, winding [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Adam Freisinger</strong> finished his studies as a Pharmacist and Health Care Manager, but ended up working as a web developer. Since then he has founded two IT companies. One of them being <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">CodeBerry</a>, a programming school that teaches web development online in english.</p>
<p>Tune in to read more about adventure games written in BASIC, winding copper wires for RAM cores and artificial intelligence. Along with that, we&#8217;ll also discuss the entrepreneur lifestyle of Adam Freisinger.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>I live in: </strong>Budapest, Hungary.</p>
<p><strong>I work:</strong> wherever my laptop is / CodeBerry programming school</p>
<p><strong>I work with:</strong> my iPhone, MacBook Air and Sublime Text.</p>
<p>I have an efficient work style.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>What do you do for a living?</strong></p>
<p>I help people learn to code.</p>
<p><strong>Tell me more about what you do regarding programming?</strong></p>
<p>I improve <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">lesson content</a> for Codeberry, so they are easier to teach and more comprehensible. This involves less coding and more creative thinking.<br />
In my free time, I fiddle with my hobby projects, that are normally tools for things I’m interested in. Recently I built the following three things:</p>
<ul>
<li>A social playlist for Spotify,</li>
<li>A Chrome extension, that quotes famous books on a new tab,</li>
<li>Software that allows me to organize my projects as well as my CodeBerry goals.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>How does your workspace look like?</strong></p>
<p>I feel best in a minimalistic environment, so my desk only contains things I use:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-5810 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Adam_Freisinger_pic1-2.jpeg" alt="That’s the place where the lessons of Codeberry are made" width="800" height="600" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">My workstation (Credit: Adam Freisinger)</p>
<p><strong>When, where and how did you learn to code?</strong></p>
<p>I got a computer when I was in elementary school and my parents thought I needed to know how to use it. So, every week a friend would come over and teach me the fundamentals. I really enjoyed writing my first run-around adventure game in BASIC.</p>
<p>I continued with things I found interesting, like writing a <a href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/dcplusplus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">DC++</a> chatbot or building a website for my father. When they published the new version of Meteor framework I couldn&#8217;t resist building a web application with it.</p>
<p>Most of my knowledge comes from searching the internet. I would browse a larger topic, then dig deeper into puzzling details.</p>
<p><strong>What are the job opportunities for web developers? On average, how much time did you spend looking for a job?</strong></p>
<p>Due to the fact that I graduated as a Pharmacist and Health Care Manager, I never looked for jobs in programming. I took on some small tasks that found me and lead to bigger tasks. Now, I&#8217;m working in my own company taking on several roles, whatever&#8217;s needed.</p>
<p>Seeing that people regularly contact me on <a href="http://linkedin.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">LinkedIn</a> and <a href="http://upwork.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">Upwork</a>, even with very little information available, this is a demanding job.</p>
<p><strong>What is your schedule like?</strong></p>
<p>I like to get up early because it&#8217;s still quiet both inside and out. I plan my day, drink some fruit juice and start working after breakfast. I also go over special events that happened on the previous day.</p>
<p>During a business week, the first one and a half days are dedicated to strategy and Friday is for reviews. Between the two I have time to work without distractions.</p>
<p>I like reviewing my personal life too, my partner and I write down each week things we enjoyed and others that need changing.</p>
<p>Twice a week I try to meet somebody for lunch that I haven&#8217;t seen for a while.</p>
<p>My weeks, months and years are similar to my days. I like to plan at the beginning of each period and look back at the end to attempt to learn from it. Every month, I collect the photos I have taken from the previous month. I also complete the <a href="http://www.yearcompass.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">YearCompass</a> every year.</p>
<p><strong>Is there something you know that would surprise everyday people?</strong></p>
<p>Programming is not magic. It mostly involves internet research. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p><strong>Who do you work with?</strong></p>
<p>I work with my friends that I have worked with for eight years on projects like Codeberry.</p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12254 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p><strong>What are the typical career paths in your profession?</strong></p>
<p>As a Pharmacist, I could have walked a well-defined life path, but I left that certainty behind. Right now, my task is to do things within the company that requires me to reach beyond the limits of what is known.</p>
<p>This gives me the opportunity to constantly learn something new and improve myself. I don&#8217;t have a certain path before me now and it makes me feel like I can become anything I want.</p>
<p><strong>What are your plans, how do you wish to continue?</strong></p>
<p>The expression &#8220;jack of all trades, master of none&#8221; describes my path best. I would like to experience as many things as I can and learn a little about each of them. I am much like a duck wanting to both fly and swim, however, not mastering either of them.</p>
<p>I hope to find a winding path between &#8220;some trades&#8221; and &#8220;all trades.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>What other profession would you choose if you had to change? Could you change?</strong></p>
<p>I wouldn’t want to change.</p>
<p><strong>What skills do great developers, IT experts require? Who do you not recommend this profession to?</strong></p>
<p>There are a few skills that don’t hurt:</p>
<ul>
<li>Strong analytical thinking,</li>
<li>An experimenting spirit,</li>
<li>Attention to details.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What’s your favourite part?</strong></p>
<p>I enjoy seeing fast results. I can change the world by simply editing a code. I would probably be a terrible nuclear power plant designer, who plans something with all their heart then, if lucky, sees the steps of their design begin several years later.</p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12018 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p><strong>What grinds your gears most? What are the difficulties and dangers of your profession?</strong></p>
<p>You no longer need to know how to build RAM modules to browse websites. Similarly, there are plenty of pre-written programs that stop you from seeing things further.</p>
<p>It makes me mad when I have to rewrite a login module, instead of taking advantage of pre-defined elements. There are too many different solutions for the same problem, we&#8217;re being inefficient this way.</p>
<p><strong>How stable is your job? How much time does one spend working for the same company?</strong></p>
<p>Right now, I’m pretty sure I would find a job.<br />
I feel lucky because I can afford to work somewhere as long as I can focus on my tasks, improve and learn new things. If this changed, I would want to quit.</p>
<p><strong>If you had to ask for one thing in the name of all developers, what would it be?</strong></p>
<p>Please don’t write the same code twice. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p><strong>How much can one earn in this profession (as a newbie, experienced and veteran)?</strong></p>
<p>Thanks to the years spent saving some money, I now have the opportunity to work for my own business. I hope we can afford some paychecks soon, as now only my enthusiasm pushes me forward.</p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12255 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p><strong>What do you think is the best way to learn to code?</strong></p>
<p>One answer doesn’t fit all, everyone has to learn the way they can do best. For me, it’s easiest via real projects. Whenever I’m stuck I just seek help.</p>
<p><strong>What makes code worth learning?</strong></p>
<p>Firstly, programming is like a foreign language; it helps understand other cultures and change your entire life if you want it to. Secondly, it’s a profession that surely won’t disappear in the next decades (or until artificial intelligence takes over).</p>
<p><strong>In the “<a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/category/meet-the-codeberry-team/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Meet the Codeberry team</a>” article series</strong> you will find interviews with our co-founders and collegues, as they are talking about what it’s like to be an IT specialist nowadays.</p>
<p><strong><em>Would you like to learn how to code? Come and <a href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">try our first lessons for free at the CodeBerry Programming School.</a></em></strong></p>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<h2></h2>
<h2 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ef5350;"><strong>Learn to code and change your career!</strong></span></h2>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 40px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12065" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>100% ONLINE</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12066" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-440x440.png 440w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4.png 512w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>IDEAL FOR BEGINNERS</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12067" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SUPPORTIVE COMMUNITY</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12068" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SELF-PACED LEARNING</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 10px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<h3 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #20c997;">Not sure if programming is for you? With CodeBerry you’ll like it.</span></h3>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 30px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-buttons aligncenter">
<div class="wp-block-button is-style-fill"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-white-color has-text-color has-background" style="border-radius: 10px; background-color: #ef5350;" href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><strong>TRY THE FIRST LESSONS FOR FREE</strong></a></div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 25px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12074" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png" sizes="(max-width: 282px) 100vw, 282px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png 564w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1-300x47.png 300w" alt="" width="282" height="45" /></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
