<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>javascript course for beginners | CodeBerry Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/en/tag/javascript-course-for-beginners-en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog</link>
	<description>Learn programming online</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 17:00:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Top 10 JavaScript courses for beginners</title>
		<link>/blog/en/javascript-courses-for-beginners/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blog-admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:11:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Programming courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best javascript courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green fox academy review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[javascript course for beginners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[javascript courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[javascript courses online]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[javascript lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[javascript lessons for beginners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[javascript lessons near me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[javascript programming course]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[javascript programming courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online javascript courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online javascript lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scrimba pricing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scrimba subscription price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shaw academy coding course]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://codeberryschool.com/blog/?p=9590</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[JavaScript in a nutshell The structure and form of a web page is built up by HTML; its style and presentation is created using CSS. And the third member of the golden triad of web development is JavaScript (or JS, for short). On the client side, JavaScript operates the functional parts of websites and it’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>JavaScript in a nutshell</h1>
<p>The structure and form of a web page is built up by HTML; its style and presentation is created using CSS. And the third member of the golden triad of web development is JavaScript (or JS, for short).</p>
<p>On the client side, JavaScript operates the functional parts of websites and it’s responsible for the user experience—practically, it brings life to the website. <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/beginners-guide-to-javascript/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">(You can learn more about it here.)</a></p>
<p>Knowing these three systems could open a host of new options for you: they can be used to create exciting, sophisticated, and substantial web content.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12017 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Besides the front end, <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/beginners-guide-to-javascript/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">JavaScript</a> is also used on the server-side or so-called backend development through Node.js &#8211; a </span><a href="https://medium.com/javascript-in-plain-english/node-js-language-or-framework-938e0936681" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">run time open source development platform</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for executing JavaScript code server-side. </span> This programming language is constantly being expanded and developed, so the scope of its use keeps growing.</p>
<p>Becoming a JavaScript programmer could be a critical addition to your skills in the quest for finding your dream job.</p>
<h2>This article lists the JavaScript courses offering to teach you the basics of JavaScript</h2>
<p>(And <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/choosing-beginner-programming-course/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">this article</a> helps you choose the right coding course by listing all relevant factors you should consider.)</p>
<h3><a href="http://codeberryschool.com/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">1. CodeBerry</a></h3>
<p>At CodeBerry you can join an <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/basics-of-programming-course" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">introductory programming course,</a> where you&#8217;ll have a solid understanding of the basics of programming in two months.</p>
<p>The course leads you from the very beginning of JavaScript to a stable knowledge which will help you to continue with an intermediate course or create your very first project based on this programming language.</p>
<p>You will learn:</p>
<ul>
<li>2 months long, 3-5 hours/week</li>
<li>Classes start at specified dates, you need to register before the beginning</li>
<li>You can learn on your own pace, but a mentor will help your work during the course</li>
<li>You can ask for help and advice whenever you need</li>
</ul>
<p>In order to participate, you need to subscribe and pay monthly for the materials &#8211; in this case, you’ll be charged 99$/month, in exchange you’ll get access to all of the materials in the “Basics of Programming” course, and you’ll get one of the CodeBerry mentors who will help you through all the time.</p>
<p>If you wouldn’t like to pay immediately, it is possible to try the first 10 lessons for free, in order to decide if it fits to you.<br />
After subscription you still have the chance to get a refund &#8211; if you are not satisfied with the program, CodeBerry pays all of your money back.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The explanations are absolutely clear and helpful, I like the page structure as well. The lessons are interesting, once I start studying, I can barely finish it. &#8211; Anita Lengyel, Codeberry-student</p>
</blockquote>
<p><div id="attachment_4627" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://cdn.pixabay.com/photo/2018/08/23/10/52/code-3625646_960_720.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-4627" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-4627 size-full" src="https://cdn.pixabay.com/photo/2018/08/23/10/52/code-3625646_960_720.jpg" alt="As a JavaScript programmer student you will learn how to code" width="2000" height="1500" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-4627" class="wp-caption-text">As a JavaScript programmer student, you will learn how to code</p></div></p>
<h3><a href="https://www.greenfoxacademy.com/" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">2. Green Fox Academy</a></h3>
<p>At the Green Fox Academy, you can choose both online and on-campus courses, which are located at Budapest, Hungary, but via the internet, you can take part from everywhere you’d like, according to a scheduled timetable.</p>
<p>After registration you have to fulfil a preliminary skill test, to examine your soft skills and way of thinking, then you’ll be sorted into one of the learning groups.</p>
<p>At the <a href="https://www.greenfoxacademy.com/en/on-campus-junior-developer-courses" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">On-campus junior course</a>, they offer a massive knowledge of what is needed for a front-end, a back-end or a full-stack developer position. You can choose from two different scheduling:</p>
<ul>
<li>Full-time course: 50-60 hours/week (5&#215;8 hours on weekdays + homework), 18 weeks+2 weeks of break</li>
<li>Part-time course: 20-25 hours/week (2&#215;3 hours on weeknights + homework) 38 weeks+5 weeks of break</li>
</ul>
<p>The course is self-financed, about the different payment options you can read more on their website.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“If you want to get a kickstart as a developer, this is the right place to get it!” &#8211; György Pataricza, Green Fox student</p>
</blockquote>
<h3><a href="https://www.udemy.com/topic/javascript/" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">3. Udemy</a></h3>
<p>At Udemy you can choose from a various range of courses depending on your needs and former knowledge.<br />
<span style="font-weight: 400;">It is worth checking the course list regularly, in order to find the ideal materials discounted. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With this option, most courses start from a very pleasant 13.99 € price, and contain online or live-performed educational materials &#8211; but if you‘re unlucky, you could find 2-300€ course prices.</span></p>
<p><strong>If you are searching for a beginner course, <a href="https://www.udemy.com/course/javascript-the-complete-guide-2020-beginner-advanced/" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">this one</a> could be a perfect choice.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>It contains 614 short lessons in approximately 52 hours.</li>
<li>Leads you from a very beginner level to advanced skills.</li>
<li>You can organise your timetable on your own (there are no scheduled classes)</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This </span><a href="https://www.udemy.com/course/javascript-beginners-complete-tutorial/" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">JavaScript Bootcamp Course</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> also could be a great start if you’d like to use JavaScript on a higher level. The materials also start from introductory level, and contain:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">483 lectures in 52 learning hours</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Downloadable materials</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Full lifetime access</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Access on mobile and TV</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">30-day money-back guarantee</span></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>If you would like to learn faster or your goal is basic knowledge about JavaScript language, you will like <a href="https://www.udemy.com/course/javascript-the-basics-for-beginners/" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">this course.</a></strong></p>
<ul>
<li>It contains 385 short lessons within 38 hours of learning materials</li>
<li>It is only about the beginner topics, the advanced level is not included</li>
<li>This one is also an online course, you can learn on your own pace</li>
</ul>
<p>If you are already done with the beginner JavaScript lessons, you also will find additional courses here, for example about object-oriented programming, data structures or algorithms.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“I have more than 20 courses done, I&#8217;m really thankful to Udemy for the ability of learning more new things. Greetings from Russia.” &#8211; Roman Bubnow, Udemy student</p>
</blockquote>
<h3><a href="https://www.pluralsight.com/browse/software-development/javascript" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">4. Pluralsight</a></h3>
<p>Pluralsight also offers a different kind of online JavaScript courses. Most of them are shorter, 2-3 hours long materials, specialised on smaller topics about JavaScript.</p>
<p>There are also bigger course-packages, like the <a href="https://www.pluralsight.com/courses/javascript-from-fundamentals-to-functional-js" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">“From fundamentals to functional JavaScript”</a> course (7+ hours long).<br />
If you would like to learn with the Pluralsight materials, you have to subscribe to the access. You can choose from 3 different options:</p>
<ul>
<li>Monthly: it costs 29.00$/month</li>
<li>Annual: it costs 24.92$/month (it will be billed annually)</li>
<li>Premium: it costs 37.42$/month (it will be billed annually)</li>
</ul>
<p>The first 10 days are free, so you can try it first and then making your decision if you’d like to continue the learning here.</p>
<p>For your licence, you will get full access to all of the 7500+ materials on the website. If you are a premium member, you also can use some additional function &#8211; about the pricing and the extras <a href="https://www.pluralsight.com/pricing/free-trial" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">you can read more here.</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12028 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-2.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-2-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-2-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><a href="https://join.shawacademy.com/online-web-design-course/" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">5. Shaw Academy</a></h3>
<p>At Shaw Academy, you will find a complete web design course, with HTML, CSS, Python and of course well-prepared JavaScript lessons.</p>
<p>The course promises to take you step-by-step on the basics of creating websites, also to teaching up-to-date knowledge in the programming languages.</p>
<p>The course has been structured into 4 modules supported by expertly designed study material and video lessons, on an easy and comfortable way.</p>
<ul>
<li>The course contains 8 interactive lessons</li>
<li>Duration: 4 weeks (8+ hours of study time)</li>
<li>Pathway to EQF Diploma (European Qualification Framework Equivalent level 5.)</li>
</ul>
<p>If you’d like to attend you have to fill a short form on the website, then you can immediately start the course.</p>
<p>The course is 100% online, no scheduled classes are involved in the material.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_4627" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://cdn.pixabay.com/photo/2016/02/07/20/38/computer-1185569_960_720.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-4627" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-4627 size-full" src="https://cdn.pixabay.com/photo/2016/02/07/20/38/computer-1185569_960_720.jpg" alt="An average workday as a JavaScript programmer" width="2000" height="1500" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-4627" class="wp-caption-text">An average workday as a JavaScript programmer</p></div></p>
<h3><a href="https://www.codecademy.com/catalog/language/javascript" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">6. Codecademy</a></h3>
<p>Just like Pluralsight, Codecademy also offers several courses for their students, depending on their personal skills and basic knowledge.</p>
<p>The courses start on different levels from beginner to advanced, and there’s also specialized contents for the coders who are interested in specific topics.</p>
<p>For example, if you’d like to start now the JS-learning, this <a href="https://www.codecademy.com/learn/introduction-to-javascript" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">“Introduction to JavaScript”</a> course might be a perfect choice.</p>
<p>At Codecademy you also can make a contract and pay monthly for the materials &#8211; in this case, you’ll be charged 19.99$/month, and for your contract, you will get:</p>
<ul>
<li>unlimited courses on mobile and computer</li>
<li>Members-only content</li>
<li>Real-world Projects</li>
<li>Step-by-step Guidance</li>
<li>Peer support</li>
<li>Certificates of completion</li>
</ul>
<p>If you don’t want to pay for the lessons, the “basic courses” are free for anyone who would like to try the Codecademy materials first.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“I know from first-hand experience that you can go in knowing zero, nothing, and just get a grasp on everything as you go and start building right away.” — Madelyn, Pinterest</p>
</blockquote>
<h3><a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/learn" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">7. FreeCodeCamp</a></h3>
<p>FreeCodeCamp is the best choice for everybody who has just decided to start coding.</p>
<p>It is a free, interactive platform, where you can learn and practice programming at the same time.</p>
<p>Besides JavaScript, you’ll find here a lot of other popular programming languages, which makes the comparison easier, if you aren’t sure yet, <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/which-programming-language-is-right-for-you/" rel="nofollow external" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank">which programming language is right for you.</a></p>
<p>The course contains a lot of micro-lessons, leading you step-by-step from an absolute beginner level to advanced programming skills.</p>
<p>At the end of every lesson, there is a coding task what you have to solve on your own, and you can immediately check your results in the interactive window &#8211; if it is not correct, it must be fixed, otherwise you can’t move to the next lesson.</p>
<p>Besides the interactive platform, there are additional information and guides about every language, such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>External courses</li>
<li>Quick courses</li>
<li>Challenges, exercises</li>
<li>Tutorials</li>
<li>Editors</li>
<li>Blogs, podcasts, video tutorials</li>
<li>Books and other additional information about JavaScript you should know</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/learn/javascript-algorithms-and-data-structures/basic-javascript/comment-your-javascript-code" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">This is how it looks like:</a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-9620 size-large" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/freecodecamp-1024x466.png" alt="This is how FreeCodeCamp JavaScript course looks like" width="1024" height="466" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/freecodecamp-1024x466.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/freecodecamp-300x137.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/freecodecamp-768x350.png 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/freecodecamp-1080x492.png 1080w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/freecodecamp.png 1366w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<blockquote>
<p>“I recommend taking the courses on here. Its really informative and you really can learn from doing the challenges.” &#8211; Alcides Gomez, Freecodecamp student about FreeCodeCamp JavaScript course.</p>
</blockquote>
<h3><a href="https://www.coursera.org/search?query=javascript&amp;" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">8. Coursera</a></h3>
<p>At Coursera there are plenty of useful JavaScript courses on different levels, durations and languages, you can filter them by every important segment.</p>
<p>Besides beginner, intermediate and advanced levels there are also mixed courses &#8211; this last one is for those who already have a basic programming background and now the goal is to broaden their knowledge.</p>
<p>You also can choose from complete courses or just specializations depending on your goals and preferences.<br />
Below we are listing 3 different courses as examples &#8211; if you would like to see more, you can find the complete list on Coursera’s website.</p>
<h4><a href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/html-css-javascript-for-web-developers" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">HTML, CSS and JS for web developers course</a> &#8211; Offered by Johns Hopkins University:</h4>
<p><em>Basic course, 5 weeks, 26 óra</em></p>
<p><strong>Course description:</strong></p>
<p><em>“In this course, we will learn the basic tools that every web page coder needs to know. We will start from the ground up by learning how to implement modern web pages with HTML and CSS. (&#8230;) You’ll be able to code up a web page that will be just as useful on a mobile phone as on a desktop computer. </em></p>
<p><em>No “pinch and zoom” required! Last but certainly not least, we will get a thorough introduction to the most ubiquitous, popular, and incredibly powerful language of the web: Javascript.”</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Many thanks to the creators of this course! It was a very solid refresher for me, even though I have spent in web development a few years by now. I thoroughly enjoyed every lesson. Thank you, Yaakov!”</p>
</blockquote>
<h4><a href="https://www.coursera.org/projects/modern-javascript-es6-basics" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">Modern JS ES6 basics</a> &#8211; Offered by Coursera</h4>
<p><em>Intermediate specialization, 2 hours<br />
Enrollment is free, desktop only</em></p>
<p>In this specialisation you learn through a split-screen video, your instructor guides you step-by-step.</p>
<p>Your workspace will be a cloud desktop right in your browser, no download required.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“I found the project much relevant for those who are going to learn react shortly. Instructure is a lovely teacher and person. I appreciate teaching skills of course instructors. Thanks! Coursera” &#8211; by MK Jul 19, 2020</p>
</blockquote>
<h4><a href="https://www.coursera.org/specializations/web-design" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">Web Design for Everybody: Basics of Web Development &amp; Coding Specialization</a> &#8211; Offered by University of Michigan</h4>
<p><em>Mixed course, 5 different courses included<br />
Free</em></p>
<p><strong>Course description:</strong></p>
<p><em>“A Coursera Specialization is a series of courses that helps you master a skill. To begin, enrol in the Specialization directly, or review its courses and choose the one you&#8217;d like to start with. When you subscribe to a course that is part of a Specialization, you’re automatically subscribed to the full Specialization. </em></p>
<p><em>It’s okay to complete just one course — you can pause your learning or end your subscription at any time. Visit your learner dashboard to track your course enrollments and your progress.”</em></p>
<p>You’ll find 5 different courses in this specialization:</p>
<ul>
<li>Introduction to HTML5</li>
<li>Introduction to CSS3</li>
<li>Interactivity with JavaScript</li>
<li>Advanced Styling with Responsive Design</li>
<li>Web Design for Everybody Capstone</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://online-learning.harvard.edu/catalog?keywords=javascript&amp;op=Search" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">9. Harvard</a></h3>
<p>In the online course offering of Harvard, you can find really cool stuff and materials which are actually official Harvard University courses &#8211; every one of them has a unique course-code as on-campus courses have, so you can tell that you actually study at Harvard. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>The Harvard online courses normally durates for 5 months (a semester), and there are fixed dates for registration.</p>
<p>These semester-long courses cost around 1800-2000$, but there are also shorter materials (11-13 weeks long) which are free and mostly contain beginner materials to a topic. For example, this course, which is called <a href="https://online-learning.harvard.edu/course/cs50-introduction-computer-science?delta=0" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">“Introduction to computer science”.</a></p>
<p>At the end of the free courses, you can get a certification about your success, but it will require a 90$ fee to get the cert.</p>
<p><strong>If you’d like to choose a paid course,</strong> it will provide you with more detailed and deeper knowledge about JavaScript and of course computer science itself.</p>
<p>This is the description of the introductory <a href="https://online-learning.harvard.edu/course/introduction-web-programming-using-javascript-4?delta=0" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">JavaScript course</a> of Harvard:</p>
<p><em>“This course provides an introduction to web development by way of the essential language and runtime environment that powers modern web interfaces. </em></p>
<p>The course provides a solid foundation in computer programming in JavaScript: syntax and data structures, conditionals, objects, scope and closures, Ajax, the DOM, and event handling. Students gain an understanding of the popular libraries that power rich web applications such as jQuery, VueJS, and others.”</p>
<p><div id="attachment_4627" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://images.pexels.com/photos/577585/pexels-photo-577585.jpeg" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-4627" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-4627 size-full" src="https://images.pexels.com/photos/577585/pexels-photo-577585.jpeg" alt="As a JavaScript developer you will have several job opportunities" width="2000" height="1500" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-4627" class="wp-caption-text">As a JavaScript developer, you will have several job opportunities</p></div></p>
<h3>10. IBM (via edX.org) &#8211; <a href="https://www.edx.org/course/introduction-to-cloud-development-with-html5-css3-and-javascript" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">Introduction to Cloud Development with HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript</a></h3>
<p>In this IBM-provided course, you’ll earn a proper knowledge to start front-end development with.</p>
<p>Besides JavaScript, they are teaching you HTML5 and CSS3 &#8211; with these three languages you will be able to build websites and start a career as a junior front-end developer.</p>
<p>The course also <strong>gives you basic information</strong> about the technical background as to how internet servers and clients work together to deliver applications to users and takes you through the context for application development in the Cloud.</p>
<ul>
<li>The course is part of a professional certificate (for 99$ &#8211; it is verified)</li>
<li>Free access for all materials</li>
<li>Duration: 4 weeks (1-2 hour/week)</li>
<li>Level: introductory</li>
</ul>
<p>Through the lessons, you will become familiar with tools like Git, GitHub and GitLab, and be able to work with them even to create a nice portfolio for your future employees.</p>
<h3>10+1. W3C (via edX.org) &#8211; <a href="https://www.edx.org/course/javascript-introduction" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">JavaScript introduction</a></h3>
<p>This introductory level course is provided by the well-known W3C (World Wide Web Consortium) which is really useful for the programmers during everyday work.</p>
<p>The course is the best choice for beginners, as for the topic included, as well as the cosy amount of content (you have to learn only 6-8 hours weekly).</p>
<p>You can join the course freely but if you’d like to get a certification you can upload on your LinkedIn profile in order to increase your chances to get a well-paid developer job, for 199$ W3C provides you with a verified certification.</p>
<ul>
<li>Part of a professional certificate (for 199$)</li>
<li>Course is free</li>
<li>Duration: 5 weeks (6-8 hours/week)</li>
<li>Level: Introductory</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Course description:</strong></p>
<p><em>“JavaScript lets you add interactive features to your Web sites, including dynamically updated content, controlled multimedia, animated images, and much more. </em></p>
<p>We present JavaScript best practices by means of many interactive examples, some of which being demonstrated in live coding videos.”</p>
<h3>10+2: <a href="https://scrimba.com/" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external">Scrimba</a></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: =;">Scrimba offers several kinds of materials on a pretty well-organised website, so you can filter the alternatives by several viewpoints.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: =;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are four big categories:</span></span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bootcamps</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Frameworks</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">JavaScript</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">HTML &amp; CSS</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As you can see, at Scrimba you’ll have the chance to get familiar with not just the programming language but the belonging techniques too like frameworks. You can also choose an extended course called “bootcamp” where they show you the practical use of the field you’ll be learning about.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Half of the courses are totally free to join, others cost around $99, but if you’re lucky, you can find courses up to 50% discount or even free access for paid materials.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Besides coding, Scrimba has special courses which can help you to improve skills like algorithmic thinking or getting familiar with new technologies, such as:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: =;"><a href="https://scrimba.com/course/gpracticalmath" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Math for front-end developers</span></a> </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://scrimba.com/course/greactmovie" rel="nofollow noopener external" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Build a movie-search app in React</span></a></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Scrimba also offers mentoring so you can get help if you are stuck on a problem. There is also a Discord channel, where you can join your “schoolmates” and reach out for some help or even infos and motivation.</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Thanks to Scrimba, I was able to quickly transition from Angular to React. I took the bootcamp and two weeks after finishing it I got a job as a React developer.” &#8211; Esteban Balcarcel, Scrimba student</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12019 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-2.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-2-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-2-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Learning JavaScript programming—diligently—is the most profitable investment without question</h2>
<p>Many companies are looking for front-end developers, and knowing JavaScript is a critical step on the road to this profession. Web programming skills can also be useful in other areas, such as in entrepreneurship or the UX scene.</p>
<p>Think about which course would be the most fitting to your goals, learning style, and schedule; research it, ask your questions and get started!</p>
<p>We hope that you found this compilation useful, and we wish you all the best in learning JavaScript.</p>
<p>For more tips on how to choose the course that’s right for you and for some help in taking the first steps, check out the articles published in our <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/category/basics-of-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Basics of Programming</a> series. If you are not set on JavaScript yet, make sure to look at our lists of <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/java-programming-courses/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Java courses</a> as well.</p>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<h2></h2>
<h2 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ef5350;"><strong>Learn to code and change your career!</strong></span></h2>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 40px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12065" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>100% ONLINE</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12066" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-440x440.png 440w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4.png 512w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>IDEAL FOR BEGINNERS</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12067" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SUPPORTIVE COMMUNITY</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12068" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SELF-PACED LEARNING</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 10px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<h3 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #20c997;">Not sure if programming is for you? With CodeBerry you’ll like it.</span></h3>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 30px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-buttons aligncenter">
<div class="wp-block-button is-style-fill"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-white-color has-text-color has-background" style="border-radius: 10px; background-color: #ef5350;" href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><strong>TRY THE FIRST LESSONS FOR FREE</strong></a></div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 25px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12074" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png" sizes="(max-width: 282px) 100vw, 282px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png 564w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1-300x47.png 300w" alt="" width="282" height="45" /></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
