<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>javascript story | CodeBerry Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/en/tag/javascript-story/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog</link>
	<description>Learn programming online</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 20:39:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>JavaScript Developer with a Social Worker Degree – The  Success Story of Our Student, Anikó Borosová</title>
		<link>/blog/en/javascript-developer-aniko-borosova/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blog-admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 11:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[CodeBerry Student Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[degree in javascript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EDMdesigner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[javascript degree]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[javascript developer blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[javascript mentor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[javascript story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[javascript worker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self taught javascript developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-taught programmer success stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sublime text student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[worker in javascript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[worker javascript]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://codeberryschool.com/blog/?p=6576</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Anikó Borosová got a degree in social work from the Eötvös Loránd University. After graduation, she worked in the social sector, then as a data processor and in customer service. Currently, she is working as a junior JavaScript developer at EDMdesigner.com. I live here: Budapest, Hungary I work here: EDMdesigner.com Kft. Time spent studying with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b>Anikó Borosová</b> <span style="font-weight: 400;">got a degree in social work from the Eötvös Loránd University. After graduation, she worked in the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">social sector</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, then as a data processor and in customer service. Currently, she is working as a junior JavaScript developer at </span><a href="https://edmdesigner.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">EDMdesigner.com</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><b>I live here:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Budapest, Hungary</span></p>
<p><b>I work here:</b> <a href="http://edmdesigner.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">EDMdesigner.com</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Kft.</span></p>
<p><b>Time spent studying with <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">CodeBerry</a></b><b>:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> 4 months</span></p>
<p><b>I work with:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> ASUS laptop with Ubuntu at work / Lenovo ThinkPad Edge running Windows 10 at home / <a href="https://www.sublimetext.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">Sublime Text</a> / I have an 11-year-old Nokia (no, not the 3310, I’m not that cool)</span></p>
<h4>When you’re asked about your profession, how do you answer?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I say programmer or <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/beginners-guide-to-javascript/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">junior JavaScript developer</a>. There aren&#8217;t any programmers or self-taught gurus around me, so I don&#8217;t usually go into details. Moreover, this is a more difficult question than</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> it seems</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to be at first. I am not a social worker anymore, but I don&#8217;t feel like a programmer yet either, it hasn&#8217;t become a part of my identity so far. It&#8217;s a weird feeling.</span></p>
<h4>What had been your job before you started coding?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After graduating as a social worker from the Eötvös Loránd University, I returned to Slovakia and started working in my field. I worked at a jobcentre and for the local government, mostly with the unemployed and socially disadvantaged clients, the homeless and a segregated Romani district. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Later I worked in data processing/customer service positions in the automobile industry.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12254 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h4>Why did you decide to start learning web development?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My previous jobs didn’t make me happy. As a social worker you hardly ever see the fruits of your efforts: Our resources and time are usually only enough for band-aid solutions, and there is only a minimal chance to achieve real change. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s like a Kafka novel: You go marching against the system, trying to help, but without adequate resources, or in a burnt-out, demotivating environment, that is more often than not, just keeps humiliating the client, you quickly lose hope, and then it’s up to you to decide whether you flee or get chewed up by the system. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I decided to flee, but working in the IT sector never occurred to me as a viable option. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Then last year I heard a lot about the ever-growing demand for developers, and all the online courses, so I decided to try one. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I liked it, and most importantly: I could see the results of my work. I improved slowly but steadily, and a couple of months later I thought to myself: It&#8217;s about time I take this more seriously, as it might actually lead to a job. And it did.</span></p>
<h4>How did you learn programming? What kind of courses, books etc. did you use?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I started at <a href="https://www.codecademy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">Codecademy</a> and <a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">FreeCodeCamp</a>, reading documentations, following video streams on the side, then I started studying with <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">CodeBerry</a>. I also attended the Bratislava workshop of <a href="http://railsgirls.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">Rails Girls</a> this summer.</span></p>
<h4>What did CodeBerry offer you? What was it like to study at our school?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Having a mentor was the greatest help for me, it proved to be the most efficient way of studying. Before CodeBerry, I used to study on my own, but that way — especially as a beginner — you can&#8217;t be sure you understand the connections and the logic properly; it&#8217;s hard to figure out what&#8217;s missing and what should be your next step. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At CodeBerry, mentorship was really effective and informal. You can ask for help anytime you reach an obstacle, and get an answer fairly quickly; even when you have 10 questions at once. This was a really positive experience compared to my earlier studies in the traditional educational system.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I also made great use of your help with </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">the preparation for the interviews. I received tips on what questions I should expect and how to respond to them. This extra knowledge helped me a lot, especially as I was switching from another profession, starting from zero in this field.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12018 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h4>Do you have any experience, tips or tricks to share with those who are just starting their studies?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It doesn&#8217;t matter if you don&#8217;t understand something at first (or second, third, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">umpteenth</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">) glance, just keep trying. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Keep at it until you succeed.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Keep looking at it until you start to see it (the advice of my high school teacher — and it is so true). There will always be obstacles, but that is no reason to give up.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ask for help, dare to ask questions, and if you find yourself home alone, stuck without answers and motivation, then simply attend an IRL (&#8220;in real life&#8221;, i.e. personal) programming event or workshop to meet and talk to other people who are in the same boat. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Rail Girls gave me a great push at the perfect moment, leaving me with a really good feeling. I returned from the workshop thinking that if my mentor (my hero, Pilar Huidobro), who also started programming at a similar event, could work as a software developer and teacher after 5 years of coding, then I can do it too, I can learn it too.</span></p>
<h4>Tell me a little about where you work now, what your duties are. What do you do on a typical day or week?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I work at </span><a href="http://edmdesigner.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">EDMdesigner</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as a JavaScript developer. We are working on the company&#8217;s e-mail content management software in smaller teams, where everyone gets his or her part of the work. Apart from this, we have a constantly growing component library for Knockouts.js, the Knob.js — I also made a new component for this. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My team&#8217;s (well, duo&#8217;s) task is user acquisition; we are working on finding out how we can achieve more registrations and subscribers. We use Google Analytics, Intercom and Hotjar.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Following the<a href="https://www.scrumguides.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"> SCRUM-method</a>, we have stand-ups every morning, where we talk about the daily tasks, obstacles and future tasks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite the difficulty, it proved to be an advantage that I had to write code from day one.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This way I get to learn the company&#8217;s workflow on the go, and I can find out how my code meshes with the already existing one, done by my coworkers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">During the past 6 weeks, I&#8217;ve only done things </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I had never done before, so I actually learn new things every day.</span></p>
<h4>Who do you work with, and how do they help your work?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is not a big company, we barely count 20 people in the office. Most colleagues are working part-time, and we also have students among us. During the stand-ups, which I mentioned before, we also talk about how I&#8217;m supposed to proceed and I can ask anybody if I&#8217;m stuck, everyone is really helpful.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_6578" style="width: 753px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-6578" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-6578 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Aniko_Borosova_pic1.jpeg" alt="This is the office where Anikó works as a javascript developer" width="743" height="557" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Aniko_Borosova_pic1.jpeg 743w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Aniko_Borosova_pic1-300x225.jpeg 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Aniko_Borosova_pic1-510x382.jpeg 510w" sizes="(max-width: 743px) 100vw, 743px" /><p id="caption-attachment-6578" class="wp-caption-text">My current workplace</p></div></p>
<h4>What software, devices and technologies do you work with currently?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I use Ubuntu, Slack, Sublime Text, terminator, GitKraken, Node.js, Jasmine, gulp, MongoDB, Redis, Docker, Nginx etc. There are also new JavaScript libraries and npm packages published daily or weekly.</span></p>
<h4>How long were you looking for a job? Was it hard to find a place to work?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My case can&#8217;t be called typical, as it took quite a bit of luck that things turned out as they did. My strategy was to apply for at least 8–10 jobs, struggle a bit at first trying to get through the interviews, but get the hang of it by the end. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I was hoping that the 10th interview or so would be successful, and they would finally offer me a job. Instead, EDMdesigner was the first place I contacted, and they were the ones who hired me. Don&#8217;t forget though, that it&#8217;s one thing to get the job, and another to be able to keep it. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I was in a total panic after the interviews, feeling I wasn&#8217;t prepared for this and that it wasn&#8217;t what I had planned. The first weeks were the most difficult, I was afraid that I won&#8217;t fit in, that I&#8217;m incapable of doing my tasks. Since then, 6 weeks have passed, and I&#8217;m still standing.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12255 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h4>How was the interview process?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There were three stages in 1–1.5 weeks. The first one was a phone interview, where they asked questions about JavaScript. After that, I had about 3 days to create a &#8220;to-do list&#8221; using JavaScript, including the HTML code. And finally, we had a Skype interview, discussing the workplace, daily tasks, the team and the job requirements.</span></p>
<h4>Do you have any advice for those who are currently preparing for a job interview?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Don&#8217;t be too nervous about it. Get enough sleep the night before. Definitely more than 2.5 hours. This is very important!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And don&#8217;t panic if you actually get the job. It will all work out.</span></p>
<h4>What is the next step for you? What direction are you taking?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&#8217;s hard to see the future – currently, there&#8217;s so much new information, that I&#8217;m happy if I manage to plan even a few days ahead. What is certain is that I still have to learn a lot of new things and tools, </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I have to improve to &#8220;level up&#8221; and be able to work more independently. I am far from being a master of JavaScript, but I hope I will get there one day.</span></p>
<p><b><i>In our <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/category/codeberry-student-stories/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">“CodeBerry Student Stories” series</a> we chat with our students who succeeded in finding a job as a developer.</i></b></p>
<h3>Would you like to do the first steps on the way to become a site builder?</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/a-brief-introduction-to-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">A Brief Introduction to Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/why-you-should-learn-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Why You Should Learn Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-much-can-you-make-as-a-programmer/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How much can you make as a programmer?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/how-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How to learn to code?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/which-programming-language-is-right-for-you/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Which programming language is good for you?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-long-it-takes-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How Long It Takes to Learn to Code</a></li>
</ul>
<p><b><i>Would you like to learn how to code? Come and try our first 25 lessons for free at the </i></b><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external"><b><i>CodeBerry Programming School</i></b></a><b>.</b></p>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<h2></h2>
<h2 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ef5350;"><strong>Learn to code and change your career!</strong></span></h2>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 40px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12065" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>100% ONLINE</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12066" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-440x440.png 440w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4.png 512w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>IDEAL FOR BEGINNERS</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12067" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SUPPORTIVE COMMUNITY</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12068" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SELF-PACED LEARNING</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 10px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<h3 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #20c997;">Not sure if programming is for you? With CodeBerry you’ll like it.</span></h3>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 30px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-buttons aligncenter">
<div class="wp-block-button is-style-fill"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-white-color has-text-color has-background" style="border-radius: 10px; background-color: #ef5350;" href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><strong>TRY THE FIRST LESSONS FOR FREE</strong></a></div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 25px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12074" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png" sizes="(max-width: 282px) 100vw, 282px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png 564w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1-300x47.png 300w" alt="" width="282" height="45" /></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
