<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>most useful programming language | CodeBerry Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/en/tag/most-useful-programming-language/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog</link>
	<description>Learn programming online</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 20:25:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Which Programming Language is Right for You?</title>
		<link>/blog/en/which-programming-language-is-right-for-you/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blog-admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 10:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Basics of Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best code language to learn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best coding language for games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best programming language for games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[code berry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CodeBerry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[game development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[most useful programming language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[most useful programming language to learn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the most beautiful programming language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[what code language should i learn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[what coding language should i learn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[what programming language should i learn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[what programming language should i learn for artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[which coding language should i learn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[which programming language should i learn]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://codeberryschool.com/blog/?p=6933</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In CodeBerry Programming School’s “Basics of Programming” series, we discuss programming-related topics and everything you need to know to get started. Stay tuned for new articles and find the answer to every “what”, “why”, and “how”, you may have had about coding! Would you like to learn how to code, online? Come and try our [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b>In CodeBerry Programming School’s “Basics of Programming” </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">series, we discuss programming-related topics and everything you need to know to get started. Stay tuned for new articles and find the answer to every “what”, “why”, and “how”, you may have had about coding!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Would you like to learn how to code, online? Come and <a href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">try our first 25 lessons for free</a> at the CodeBerry Programming School.</span></p>
<h3>Basics of Programming</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/basics-of-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Basics of Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/a-brief-introduction-to-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">A Brief Introduction to Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/why-you-should-learn-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Why You Should Learn Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-much-can-you-make-as-a-programmer/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How much can you make as a programmer?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How to learn to code?</a></li>
<li><strong>Which programming language is good for you?</strong></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-long-it-takes-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How Long It Takes to Learn to Code</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/choosing-beginner-programming-course/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How to find the right beginner programming course for you?</a></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You’ve read the articles, searched the web, and done all the research you can on programming. Now, it’s time to finally make the big decision: “what programming language should I learn?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Great question. Fortunately for you, we have a step-by-step guide that will help you decide what your motivation is for learning to code and which programming languages you should then learn.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12123 alignright" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/1-683x1024.png" alt="" width="304" height="456" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/1-683x1024.png 683w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/1-200x300.png 200w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/1-768x1152.png 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/1.png 800w" sizes="(max-width: 304px) 100vw, 304px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even if you’re still in the searching stage, this guide should give you some clarity regarding the purpose of the most common programming languages and your preferred niche. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’ve also identified four distinct ways to rank the top programming languages: by </span><b>popularity</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><b>ease-of-learning, earning potential</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and </span><b>usefulness</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Disclaimer: In this article, we’ve grouped markup languages, such as HTML and CSS, and scripting languages, such as Bash/Shell and SQL, into the category of programming languages.</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let’s start with a list of the top ten most popular programming languages according to <a href="https://insights.stackoverflow.com/survey/2018/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">StackOverflow</a>:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In this list, we see JavaScript, HTML, and CSS taking the top 3 spots for the most popular programming languages. These three languages are the backbone of front-end web development and serve as a great starting point for beginners. SQL is used for database management and the rest, such as Java, Python, C#, PHP, and C++, are general-purpose languages that you can use for a variety of tasks. Bash/Shell, on the other hand, is a command language used to communicate with Unix-based operating systems, like Linux and macOS.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12017 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What about the easiest languages to learn? </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12124 alignleft" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/3-683x1024.png" alt="" width="300" height="450" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/3-683x1024.png 683w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/3-200x300.png 200w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/3-768x1152.png 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/3.png 800w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fortunately, many of the most popular programming languages are also the easiest to learn. However, we also find some more obscure programming languages, such as R and Erlang. R is a coding language designed for statistical computing and mathematics and is a great tool for data analysis (which we’ll discuss later in the article). Erlang is primarily used for telecommunication and is present in many messaging applications, such as WhatsApp.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8230;and the top-paying programming languages? </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12125 alignright" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/5-683x1024.png" alt="" width="314" height="471" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/5-683x1024.png 683w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/5-200x300.png 200w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/5-768x1152.png 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/5.png 800w" sizes="(max-width: 314px) 100vw, 314px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re new to programming, you probably didn’t recognize many of the languages on this list. Since computer programming is a rapidly evolving industry, the highest-paid skills tend to be related to the newest, most cutting edge technologies. However, knowledge of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript is enough to get you started in your career—other languages can wait. </span></p>
<h2><b>Overview</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Besides salary, popularity, and ease of learning, you probably have your own personal motivations to learn a specific programming language. In the area below, we’ll examine some of the determining factors that might help you decide on a programming language and what uses they have. </span></p>
<h2><b>Choosing a Language by Usefulness</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is where things get a bit more complicated. How “useful” a language is to you will depend on what you’d like to accomplish with code. For example, HTML and CSS might be extremely useful to a front-end web developer, while Swift and Java are more useful to a mobile developer. Some programming languages, like Python, are designed for general purpose use, but many others are specialized tools that will help you complete specific tasks. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">First, let’s determine why you want to learn to code, decide what area you’d like to focus on, and then find the programming language that is right for you:</span></p>
<h2><b>I Want to Be a Professional Developer</b></h2>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Game Developer</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re passionate about becoming a game developer, there are two main programming languages that you’ll have to master: C++ and C#. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’d like to develop fun, 2D mobile games that are based on community and online interaction, C# is definitely the choice for you. C# is easier to learn and less complicated than C++, making it the main programming language of indie and mobile games. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">C++, on the other hand, delivers incredible power and can be used for 3D mobile games and “AAA” titles for PC and console. To create video games with the best performance and the most beautiful graphics, C++ is the way to go. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Web Developer</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In our article, “<a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/a-brief-introduction-to-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">A Brief Introduction to Programming</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">”</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, we talked a lot about the big three programming languages for web development: HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. HTML handles the format, CSS determines the style, and JavaScript makes the page come alive. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For web developers who focus primarily on UX (user experience), HTML5 and JavaScript are their most commonly used tools. Web developers involved in e-commerce, however, shift their focus to more advanced languages, such as Java, Ruby, Python, PHP, and C#. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Web programmers for small businesses will probably use PHP, while programmers for recent startups use Java, Ruby, and JavaScript for most of their work. Enterprise web developers tend to use C# and Java more often for bigger, Windows-based applications. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mobile Developer</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mobile development is a bit more straightforward and only requires you to know one programming language per operating system. </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6957" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/rami-al-zayat-170349-unsplash-1.jpg" alt="" width="5184" height="3456" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/rami-al-zayat-170349-unsplash-1.jpg 5184w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/rami-al-zayat-170349-unsplash-1-300x200.jpg 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/rami-al-zayat-170349-unsplash-1-768x512.jpg 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/rami-al-zayat-170349-unsplash-1-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/rami-al-zayat-170349-unsplash-1-1080x720.jpg 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 5184px) 100vw, 5184px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you want to create mobile apps for the iPhone or iPad, all you need to know is Swift, Apple’s own programming language for iOS. Introduced in 2014, Swift is a very powerful language that was designed to allow you to program nearly any Apple device. With knowledge of Swift, you can also write applications for Mac, the Apple Watch, and Apple TV!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mobile development for Android has taken off in recent years and has grown to surpass the popularity of development for iOS. Android is based on Java, making it super easy to learn if you already have experience using the language. You can also go from developing apps for Android to doing a ton of other cool things after you’ve gained the experience in Java. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last, but not least, we come to the Windows phone. The Windows mobile OS runs on C#, one of Microsoft’s very own programming languages. Coding in C# is an extremely valuable skill that any Windows developer should know. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, we are seeing the lines begin to blur as both mobile and desktop become more unified. Rather than being separated by mobile and desktop, programming languages are instead segregated by the ecosystem (Microsoft, Google, and Apple). Google even developed their own language called “Go”, which we might see in the future as a replacement for Java in Android. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Desktop Software</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As we mentioned above, the same programming languages that you’ll need for mobile development can be used to develop desktop software as well. If you’re interested in developing software for Windows platforms, you’ll want to learn C#. To develop cross-platform software and programs for Mac, you should learn Java and Swift, respectively. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are also several strong, web-based solutions for developing cross-platform desktop software with just HTML, CSS and JavaScript, such as </span><a href="https://electronjs.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Electron</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12028 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-2.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-2-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-2-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data Science</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the field of data science, Python and R are the most useful languages you can learn. Python is like a swiss army knife of programming languages that were designed for general purpose use. However, the strength of Python comes from the vast wealth of free data analysis libraries that are packed full of capabilities. One of the most popular data analysis libraries, Pandas, comes with tools that allow you to import information from spreadsheets or processing sets for time-series analysis. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">R is another programming language that is geared towards statistical analysis and graphing. With R, you can include </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">linear and nonlinear modeling, classical statistical tests, time-series analysis, classification, clustering, and more.</span></p>
<h2><b>I Want to Run a Startup</b></h2>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Web</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Web-based startups have a lot of options when it comes to choosing a programming language. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For e-commerce startups, PHP is a great language to start with. WordPress runs on PHP and is a great starting platform for e-commerce websites.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you want to start a SaaS (Software as a Service) startup, Java is a necessary language to learn. With Java, you’ll be able to develop software for a huge variety of platforms, from Android to Windows.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thanks to the Ruby on Rails framework, Ruby is a powerful, easy-to-use language that makes prototyping a breeze. As a high-level language, you’ll be able to create prototypes quickly and bring your idea to life with minimal effort.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Finally, we have JavaScript which directly affects the overall performance of your website. Since your startup is web-based, the performance and user experience is extremely important. These days, search engines like Google will punish you and lower your search results rankings for a slow loading and laggy site. This can make a huge impact on the number of visitors and conversions you receive.</span></p>
<h2><b>I Want to Run a Startup (Version 2.0) </b></h2>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Web</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since the storefront of an online shop is a website, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript will be necessary for the front-end. However, you do have plenty of options for the back-end, which accounts for all of the “behind-the-scenes” operations of your online store. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For handling the back-end, you’ll most likely use Node.js (JavaScript), Ruby, or PHP. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Of the three, Node.js is the most popular and widely used, both because of its speed and its basis in JavaScript. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since your startup is web-based, the performance and user experience is extremely important. These days, search engines like Google will punish you and lower your search results rankings for a slow loading and laggy site. This can make a huge impact on the amount of visitors and conversions you receive. Therefore, we would recommend the fastest option, Node.js, for the back end. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In extreme cases, you may need to learn Python or R for the back end of your site, but only if you’re dealing with huge amounts of customer or product data. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’d like an easier solution that’s already set up for you, try building your e-commerce shop in WordPress, a PHP-based solution. With WordPress, you can use a drag-and-drop interface to construct the façade of your store, while the program takes care of the front end and back end. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although WordPress is relatively easy to use, you’ll still want to learn the language or hire a PHP developer to add any additional features or troubleshoot problems as they arise. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mobile</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mobile-based startups like Uber are quite popular and successful at the moment. To launch a startup in the mobile space, it’s important that you create apps that are available on both iPhone and Android. It’s actually possible to develop cross-platform applications in Java using React Native, Ionic, PhoneGap, or Cordova, but it’s recommended that you learn the native programming languages for each platform for the best performance.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re not able to code it all yourself, hiring a mobile developer that specializes in a specific operating system can be helpful. You’ll need to hire a Java developer for Android, a Swift developer for iOS, a rare talent that may know both, or opt for a cross-platform solution. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Game</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a startup, you likely won’t have the money and resources to develop ‘AAA’ titles like the big studios. Instead, indie developers tend to focus on storyline and creativity when developing games. C++ is complicated, takes time, and is often difficult to use, meaning that it’s not your best choice as a startup. C# is easier to use and will allow you to release games more quickly and on time. </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6956" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/gaming-1.jpg" alt="" width="4928" height="3264" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/gaming-1.jpg 4928w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/gaming-1-300x199.jpg 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/gaming-1-768x509.jpg 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/gaming-1-1024x678.jpg 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/gaming-1-1080x715.jpg 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 4928px) 100vw, 4928px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Web-based games are another great place to start for new game developers. Through HTML5 and JavaScript, you can create incredible games. To find out what kind of games you can develop with HTML5 and JavaScript, check out this article: </span><a href="https://tutorialzine.com/2015/02/30-amazing-games-made-only-with-html5" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://tutorialzine.com/2015/02/30-amazing-games-made-only-with-html5</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, if you have the patience, skills, and dedication to create an amazing 3D game, you should learn C++. This powerful programming language from Microsoft is just about all you need to create stunning games for console and PC. </span></p>
<h2><b>I Want to Build Something Fun</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The most appealing aspect of programming is not only that it’s useful and highly paid, but also that it can be a lot of fun. If you want to create something cool with coding, you should first consider what kinds of projects interest you. Would you like to create a new mobile app, a web-based game, or even your own AI? Perhaps, you’d like to automate your daily tasks at work or create something for Google Apps (G-Suite)? With a good understanding of the following languages, your imagination will be the only limit to what you can create. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Small Games</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Don’t think you need to be a professional programmer to begin following your dream as a game developer; all you need to know is HTML5, JavaScript, and some WebGL. Both Doodle Jump and the incredibly famous (or infamous) mobile game, Flappy Bird, are powered by HTML5 and JavaScript. Sure, you won’t be making ‘AAA’ games for consoles any time soon, but you’ll be surprised by what you can create with limited knowledge of coding. For slightly more advanced games on desktop, you’ll want to utilize languages like C# and Python. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Google Apps (G-Suite)</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">JavaScript is the backbone for creating apps within the Google ecosystem, or the G-Suite, as it is commonly referred to. Google claims that any web apps in the G-Suite can be created with JavaScript and nothing more. This is a bit of an odd claim, considering that Gmail is actually written in Java, not JavaScript. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Regardless, learning</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> JavaScript is not necessary to create apps in G-Suite anymore. Instead, the new Google App Maker gives you a drag-and-drop interface that allows you to create custom applications and provides you with APIs for all of Google’s applications, such as Google Maps and Google Translate. The API, or Application Program Interface, is the key that enables the communication between other Google apps and your own custom app. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Task Automation</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Have you ever spent countless hours updating a spreadsheet, renaming files, or reorganizing items with your keyboard and mouse? During that mind-numbing experience, did you ever stop to think that there might be a better way? Task Automation is an entire field of programming that is dedicated to automating the boring, mindless tasks that a human would rather not do. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Using basic general-purpose languages like Python and Ruby, you can tell your computer to do all of the grunt work for you. Beyond saving time and stress, automating daily tasks will result in more accurate work, since we tend to make mistakes as we get tired, distracted, and bored. Computers, on the other hand, put their heads down and get the work done without fail.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12019 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-2.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-2-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-2-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Simple AI (Artificial Intelligence)</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In recent years, Python has become increasingly popular in the field of Artificial Intelligence. One of the greatest challenges for software developers of AI is the problem of “deep learning”, which is the ability to learn as a human does. Today, “neural mapping” is a widely-used technique in AI that involves creating large decision-making branches. Each connection is treated as if it were a neuron and a synapse in the brain. Using this technique, researchers in AI hope to create a replica of the brain that reasons and even has the creative capacities like that of a human.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">TensorFlow is a great library of resources for Python and other programming languages. While it was primarily developed for use with Python, TensorFlow.js has been released for JavaScript with the intention of using machine learning on the web. In other words, you can even use JavaScript to experiment with AI through the use of TensorFlow. </span></p>
<h2><b>Conclusion </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We hope that you enjoyed our article and now have a clearer idea of which programming language is right for you. Languages like HTML, CSS, and JavaScript are the best languages to start with, but you definitely can’t go wrong with a great, multi-purpose language like Python and C#.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Please let us know in the comments which programming languages you are currently learning and what motivated you to learn them. See you in the next article!</span></p>
<p><b>In CodeBerry Programming School’s “Basics of Programming” </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">series, we discuss programming-related topics and everything you need to know to get started. Stay tuned for new articles and find the answer to every “what”, “why”, and “how”, you may have had about coding!</span></p>
<h3>Basics of Programming</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/basics-of-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Basics of Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/a-brief-introduction-to-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">A Brief Introduction to Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/why-you-should-learn-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Why You Should Learn Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-much-can-you-make-as-a-programmer/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How much can you make as a programmer?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How to learn to code?</a></li>
<li><strong>Which programming language is good for you?</strong></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-long-it-takes-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How Long It Takes to Learn to Code</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/choosing-beginner-programming-course/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How to find the right beginner programming course for you?</a></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Would you like to learn how to code, online? Come and <a href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">try our first 25 lessons for free</a> at the CodeBerry Programming School.</span></p>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<h2></h2>
<h2 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ef5350;"><strong>Learn to code and change your career!</strong></span></h2>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 40px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12065" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>100% ONLINE</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12066" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-440x440.png 440w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4.png 512w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>IDEAL FOR BEGINNERS</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12067" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SUPPORTIVE COMMUNITY</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12068" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SELF-PACED LEARNING</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 10px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<h3 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #20c997;">Not sure if programming is for you? With CodeBerry you’ll like it.</span></h3>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 30px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-buttons aligncenter">
<div class="wp-block-button is-style-fill"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-white-color has-text-color has-background" style="border-radius: 10px; background-color: #ef5350;" href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><strong>TRY THE FIRST LESSONS FOR FREE</strong></a></div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 25px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12074" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png" sizes="(max-width: 282px) 100vw, 282px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png 564w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1-300x47.png 300w" alt="" width="282" height="45" /></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
