<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>student community | CodeBerry Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/en/tag/student-community/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog</link>
	<description>Learn programming online</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 20:27:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Programming: Private Mentorship or Online Class?</title>
		<link>/blog/en/private-mentorship-python-tutor/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blog-admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 20:50:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips and tricks for beginner programmers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Askademic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[First Tutors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mentorship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online mentor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online programming course]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online tutor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[private tutor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming course]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming teacher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spires]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[student community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[timetable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tutor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tutor Hunt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://codeberryschool.com/blog/?p=11142</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Advantages and Difficulties  Every learning form has its own advantages, and there are always some difficulties that need to be overcome as well. There are different needs to be met if you want to get to know a programming language from the basics, or if you want to prepare for an exam. In this article, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Advantages and Difficulties </span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Every learning form has its own advantages, and there are always some difficulties that need to be overcome as well. There are different needs to be met if you want to get to know a programming language from the basics, or if you want to prepare for an exam.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>In this article, we’ll talk about the advantages and disadvantages of</strong> learning programming with <strong>private mentorship and online courses.</strong> We’ll also touch on the important roles of mentors and learning communities.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12254 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Private Programming Tutor </span></h3>
<p><div style="width: 298px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" src="https://images.pexels.com/photos/4339796/pexels-photo-4339796.jpeg?auto=compress&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;h=750&amp;w=1260" alt="Mentorship has several advantages if you like to learn on your own pace." width="288" height="432" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Credit: <a href="https://www.pexels.com/photo/man-love-people-woman-4339796/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">Pexels</a></p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An undeniable advantage of having a tutor is that<strong> they can help us advance, guide our learning experience, and we don’t have to rely only on our self-discipline.</strong> This means it is not only on our diligence to learn to program—we also have to respect another person’s time and efforts. There is a prearranged schedule to meet online or in person, and most people probably find it easier to learn this way than if they have to find time for it themselves. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are many ways to learn independently as well, and you don’t need to have social contacts for some of them. For those who need social interactions, having a tutor can be a fantastic choice. <strong>Most people choose online education, so they can form social connections but don’t have to be in the same place physically.</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Having a tutor can also provide you with a completely<strong> customized learning experience,</strong> while courses aren’t customized to our personal tastes. A tutor can also notice and make up for some gaps in your knowledge that you might not even notice.</span></p>
<p><strong>Tutors can go back to the basics if need be, can teach you mathematical and logical skills that are not in the curriculum, and they can help you develop your English skills as well.</strong></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Online Programming courses</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Things that some people find helpful, others find difficult—in the case of tutoring, it can be difficult for some to adjust to a specific schedule. If someone’s schedule is always changing, private tutoring can be hard to manage. In this case, individual learning can be the solution as it is much more flexible.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If a course is based on continuous feedback, like </span><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">CodeBerry’s courses</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, you don’t have to wait for a teacher to give you feedback or wait a whole week for someone to check your home assignments—<strong>you get immediate feedback on your skills and progress.</strong> With courses in which <strong>you can practice your newly learned skills</strong> and answer questions about what you learned, you’ll immediately catch on if you misunderstood something, meaning you can learn the correct information.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With an online course, <strong>you get a curriculum you can always access,</strong> <strong>explanations that are always there,</strong> while a tutor’s explanations only stay with you if you write them down. During learning, it can be really helpful to go back to a definition and read it again if you forgot it</span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mentorship</span></h4>
<p><div style="width: 410px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" src="https://images.pexels.com/photos/4144923/pexels-photo-4144923.jpeg?auto=compress&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;dpr=2&amp;h=650&amp;w=940" alt="" width="400" height="267" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Credit: <a href="https://www.pexels.com/photo/person-writing-on-notebook-4144923/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">Pexels</a></p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Naturally, a <strong>mentor can help you when you get stuck and give you customized explanations, just like a private tutor.</strong> Mentors are more “energy, time and cost-efficient” than a tutor because they only help when you actually need help. You don’t have to work together on materials you can learn alone. If there are some things you already know and understand, you can complete them independently, fast. <strong>A mentor is a teacher you can call whenever you need them, but they won’t stand over your shoulder during the whole learning process.</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On advanced levels, where you need to complete complex individual tasks or create projects, <strong>mentors can check your work, help you improve with their suggestions, and recommend changes</strong> that you might find helpful.</span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">Online Learning Community</span></h4>
<p><strong>Having an online learning community like at <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/hu" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">CodeBerry’s courses</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong> can give you the motivation</strong> to get through the harder tasks with your fellow students and can also give you support and encouragement.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Beyond community cohesion, a very important benefit of communicating with fellow students is the <strong>opportunity to learn from each other.</strong> You can learn from the questions asked and answered by others, but you can also answer your fellow students’ questions. The latter is important because we need to organize our thoughts when we try to explain things, so <strong>we can deepen our knowledge by helping others.</strong></span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">What About Prices? </span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Different learning forms have different advantages, but how much do we need to spend to get these advantages? Independent progress doesn’t cost that much, and we collected some awesome tips for you in our article titled </span><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/hu/programozas-ingyen/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">4+1 simple ways to learn programming for free</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you want to learn with a<strong> private tutor,</strong> you have to spend a bit more. <strong>Hourly rates start from 10-12 dollars,</strong> but the average is $20 per hour. However, there are even pricier options as well. For some tutors, you have to pay $40 for 60 minutes. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Programming courses</strong> offer you other financial constructs so their prices differ significantly. An hour <strong>can cost anywhere between $5 and $12</strong>, but there are courses that are more costly.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>At CodeBerry, an hour costs less than $4</strong> if we are counting 5 hours per week for our three-month courses.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12018 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Where Can We Find Private Tutors?</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Facebook seems to be an obvious choice, we can ask our friends to introduce the mysteries of programming to us. <strong>There are also groups on </strong></span><strong>Facebook, where you can search for private tutors:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/521438201822480/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Private tutor</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/943457715686804/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Online tutors</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/1177842622291932/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tutor needed</span></a></li>
</ul>
<p><b>There are also websites with private tutoring ads</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">—we just have to type “programming” into a search engine, and we can look at everything on offer. Here are the best ones:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><a href="https://spires.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spires</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.tutorhunt.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">Tutor Hunt</a></li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://www.firsttutors.com/uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">First Tutors</a></li>
<li aria-level="1"><a href="https://askademic.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">Askademic</a></li>
</ul>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Programming With Private Tutors or Programming Courses? Which is More Effective?</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In order to answer this, <strong>we have to know our own learning style</strong> and think through our situation. If we want to prepare for an exam or a job interview, or if we want to get answers to specific questions, a private tutor might be the better choice.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>If you want to learn a new programming language</strong> or the basics of programming through practice,<strong> a course can also be a great choice.</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, we don’t have to worry about the effectiveness of online courses that require individual learning over on-site courses if we have some self-discipline and can concentrate on our tasks to progress.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you get properly created, easy to follow learning materials, you won’t be less effective learning at home than on-site, and this has been proven by a </span><a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/pdf/jeductechsoci.19.4.59.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">scientific study</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as well. In the experiment, a group learned Java programming in a traditional classroom environment, while another group learned with the help of tutorial videos with screen recordings of the programming interface combined with short explanations. The group that learned individually did better during the experiment than the group that learned on-site.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">How Much Are My Programming Skills Worth if I Didn’t Get Them at a University?</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If we look at the trends of today, we can answer the question above with the following: they are worth more and more. There are many programming job offers that don’t need an engineering degree. Most of the time, it is enough for you to do well during tasks in the entrance exam and having convincing references. Where you got your programming skills is not as important.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>We can learn programming with courses, bootcamps, or even individually.</strong> If our knowledge is sound and we have enough experience, we have a good chance when applying for most any job.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to the statistics of the programming forums at Stack Overflow,<strong> almost 30% of programmers don’t have a university degree.</strong> Another interesting fact is that those with <strong>a degree don’t always get their diploma in IT areas: almost 40% have a degree in other fields.</strong></span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_11143" style="width: 905px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-11143" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-11143 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/stat.png" alt="" width="895" height="537" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/stat.png 895w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/stat-300x180.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/stat-768x461.png 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/stat-627x376.png 627w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/stat-440x264.png 440w" sizes="(max-width: 895px) 100vw, 895px" /><p id="caption-attachment-11143" class="wp-caption-text">Credit: Stack Overflow Insights &#8211; Developer survey</p></div></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One motto of today is <strong>lifelong learning.</strong> It is not an empty phrase, but a crucial feature of programmers. Nothing represents this more than the diagram above that shows convincing data about the popularity and success of individual learning.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">86,8% of people learned a programming language, framework, or tool by themselves. 60,1% of them took online courses in programming or software development.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you want to try the opportunities given by amazing online learning materials, student communities and mentors, choose </span><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/hu" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">CodeBerry’s courses</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and be part of our learning group!</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12254 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p><strong>If you need more tricks or advice, check out the following articles too</strong> – in these, we are writing about our own experiences and ideas that might help you to get really good chances at a job interview or earn some more additional skills to improve your programming knowledge!</p>
<ul>
<li><a class="rank-math-link" href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/interview-tips-that-will-give-you-confidence-and-help-you-land-a-dev-job/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Interview tips that will give you confidence and help you land a dev job</a></li>
<li><a class="rank-math-link" href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/things-i-wish-someone-had-told-me-when-i-was-learning-how-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Things I Wish Someone Had Told Me When I Was Learning How to Code – And what I’ve learned from teaching others</a></li>
<li><a class="rank-math-link" href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/category/basics-of-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Basics of programming</a></li>
<li><a class="rank-math-link" href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/basics-of-seo-beginner/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">SEO Basics – The structure of a healthy website</a></li>
<li><a class="rank-math-link" href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/software-developer-software-engineer/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Is there a difference between a programmer and a developer?</a></li>
<li><a class="rank-math-link" href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/remote-work-home-office/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">The 15 most common jobs that can be done remotely – remote work in 2020</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/most-popular-programming-languages/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">11 most popular programming languages that always will give you a job opportunity</a></li>
<li><strong>Programming: Private Teacher or Online Class?</strong></li>
</ul>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<h2></h2>
<h2 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ef5350;"><strong>Learn to code and change your career!</strong></span></h2>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 40px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12065" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>100% ONLINE</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12066" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-440x440.png 440w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4.png 512w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>IDEAL FOR BEGINNERS</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12067" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SUPPORTIVE COMMUNITY</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12068" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SELF-PACED LEARNING</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 10px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<h3 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #20c997;">Not sure if programming is for you? With CodeBerry you’ll like it.</span></h3>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 30px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-buttons aligncenter">
<div class="wp-block-button is-style-fill"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-white-color has-text-color has-background" style="border-radius: 10px; background-color: #ef5350;" href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><strong>TRY THE FIRST LESSONS FOR FREE</strong></a></div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 25px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12074" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png" sizes="(max-width: 282px) 100vw, 282px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png 564w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1-300x47.png 300w" alt="" width="282" height="45" /></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to find the right beginner programming course for you?</title>
		<link>/blog/en/choosing-beginner-programming-course/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blog-admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 07:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Basics of Programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[application]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apprenticeship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[back-end]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beginner programming course]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beginner programming courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beginner programming jobs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[can you learn programming on your own]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[changing career]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[course length]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[front-end]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getting an IT job]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[job guarantee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mothers with small children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postpaid for students]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming course for kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming courses with job guarantee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remote learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-paced]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[student community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web development]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://codeberryschool.com/blog/?p=8900</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In CodeBerry Programming School’s “Basics of Programming” series, we discuss programming-related topics and everything you need to know to get started. Stay tuned for new articles and find the answer to every “what”, “why”, and “how”, you may have had about coding! Would you like to learn how to code, online? Come and try our [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b>In CodeBerry Programming School’s <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/category/basics-of-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">“Basics of Programming”</a> </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">series, we discuss programming-related topics and everything you need to know to get started. Stay tuned for new articles and find the answer to every “what”, “why”, and “how”, you may have had about coding!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Would you like to learn how to code, online? Come and <a href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">try our first 25 lessons for free</a> at the CodeBerry Programming School.</span></p>
<h3>Basics of Programming</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/basics-of-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Basics of Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/a-brief-introduction-to-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">A Brief Introduction to Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/why-you-should-learn-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Why You Should Learn Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-much-can-you-make-as-a-programmer/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How much can you make as a programmer?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How to learn to code?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/which-programming-language-is-right-for-you/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Which programming language is good for you?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/how-long-it-takes-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How Long It Takes to Learn to Code</a></li>
<li><strong>How to find the right beginner programming course for you?</strong></li>
</ul>
<h2>Before you begin—Step 0</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’ve been considering getting to know the world of coding, you may want to get an idea of the available options for learning the basics first. To be able to choose from the various courses in the market, you have to know what you can expect from different introductory, junior programmer, and developer courses. That is what we were trying to help you with by compiling this summary.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12017 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h2>Changing career, returning to the labor market with kids, or finding programming courses for kids?</h2>
<h3>There is a course for you, whatever your situation may be</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The structure of the training courses mostly depends on the target group they are designed for. Programs aimed at children, high school students, people wanting to change careers or mothers trying to return to the labor market are paced differently and use different methodologies. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Younger students can practice the basics of analytical thinking and programming in a fun way. Mothers can join training programs that accommodate their lifestyle while they have small children: these programs organize child care services next to the classroom and adjust the schedule so that it supports family life, helping them develop a new routine allowing mothers to learn a new profession.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Those wanting to study while also working or in university can choose from part-time courses. Others might want to get the skills necessary to start building their career in IT sooner, in a matter of months or even weeks. For them, bootcamps will be the perfect option: although these require 8–10 hours spent on studying daily, which is the equivalent of a full-time job, they offer a super fast-paced learning experience.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, the structure of a course does not necessarily depend on the target audience entirely. Some technologies simply cannot be learned with a few months’ intensive training. The next part of the article will talk about technologies and some other factors affecting the available selection of courses.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some of the courses available for various target groups</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Coding bootcamps, activities, courses for kids: </span>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.idtech.com/paths/coding" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">iDTech</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.logiscool.com/be-en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Logiscool</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">freeCodeCamp</span></a></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.activityhero.com/activities/kids-coding-classes-camps" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">ActivityHero</span></a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Programming courses</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">for parents with small kids:</span>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.zaniaclearning.com/programs/coding-parents/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Zaniac</span></a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Courses for learning a new profession, for starting a career in IT: </span><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">CodeBerry</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://www.codeavengers.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Code Avengers</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://www.codecademy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Codecademy</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://codecool.com/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Codecool</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://www.pluralsight.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pluralsight</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span></li>
</ul>
<h2>What would you like to do in the future; what job can you see yourself doing?</h2>
<h3>Your choice of technology should depend on this</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Various fields and positions in IT require knowledge of different technologies. In order to choose the right programming language to learn, you should figure out what you want to do exactly in the early stages of planning your new career. Full-stack web developers need an entirely different set of skills than what is required for developing games or working with artificial intelligence. Different career paths come with different working conditions and different salary ranges, and the programming languages you need to learn will always depend on which direction you want to take. As a programmer, you can be a freelancer, launch your own project, or work as an employee of a small start-up or a multinational company.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’d like to work at a big company with a secure background, you might need more complex programming knowledge. Completing a Java programming course</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">will give you valuable skills that can be used in countless areas, while learning the highly complex C++ programming language (which is definitely not recommended for beginners) will make you a very valuable employee.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are android programming courses especially designed for creating mobile applications, and you can get into various areas of web development through front-end and back-end technologies. A solid grasp and application of the HTML, CSS, and JavaScript languages alone can be enough for building sophisticated and substantial web pages, but for delving into data science, you will want to opt for languages such as R or Python. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We could go on, but the point has been made: start in the direction that will take you to your chosen destination. </span></p>
<h2>Course length, schedule, pace and mentoring</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As we have mentioned at the beginning of the article, programming schools offer courses of various lengths: a few weeks, months, or even a couple of years. The length of a course depends on the volume of the learning material and the course schedule.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Courses that can be completed within a few weeks mostly function as an introduction to the world of coding; they help you decide whether this path is right for you and which direction to take. Super intensive courses, or bootcamps, usually take up your whole day, and they give you the capabilities necessary for starting a new career, a complex set of web development skills for example, within a few months. Other programming courses take up only a couple of hours of your time every week, but they will last for many months and you will probably have to do homework too.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another significant factor to consider is whether it is an online course, or one held offline, in a real classroom. The benefit of on-campus training is that you can work together with the student community in real time and space, it can give you external motivation and reassurance, and you can use the professional equipment and technology installed there.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12028 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-2.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-2-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-2-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Online courses vary in their schedule, which can be set as remote teaching with a fixed class schedule and group work, or it could let students progress at their own pace entirely. Choosing this option has the benefit of being able to study anywhere, usually with a partially or fully flexible schedule, at your own pace. Having the option to set your own schedule is great, but it needs serious perseverance and some self-discipline to make the most of it. Of course, these are also important if you progress together with a school or community. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Your progress will be guided by a mentor most often, but various schools have different solutions in this regard. There could be a single mentor for a whole group of students, or mentors could be assigned to each student individually. A rather common approach is to let the students progress on their own, with the option of asking questions and getting answers from a mentor anytime. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If mentoring is not part of the given course, you might still be able to ask questions and support each other in a virtual student community. Of course, there are also curriculums that you will have to learn all by yourself. </span></p>
<h2>The role of practice in the learning process</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like any new skill you learn, programming needs a lot of practice before you can use it confidently. Not every course incorporates the same amount of theory and practical exercises in its curriculum. Some schools focus on creating a project together, where you can learn your new skills by working through each stage of the project. Others let you code on your own to create a website, application, game, etc. There are even courses using agile methods, coaching, and teamwork to simulate a corporate environment. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Certain programming schools arrange apprenticeships for their graduated students at partner companies, so that they can deepen their knowledge as paid interns.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12019 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-2.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-2-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Self-paced-2-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h2>Programming schools with job guarantee? Prepaid or postpaid options?</h2>
<h3>A short note on payment structures</h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Many programming schools now offer to support you in finding a job, and some provide a full job guarantee. That means that if you cannot find a suitable job within a certain time period after completing the course, you get a refund, or in case of postpaid courses, you don’t have to pay the tuition fee. If your job hunt is successful, you can pay the course fees from the salary you earn as a programmer in the postpaid system. There is a wide range of coding courses in terms of fees and payment options, including free programming courses, state-funded education, and various scholarships.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As you can see, there are many options to choose from—you just need to find the one that’s best for you. The multitude of available courses might seem a little overwhelming now, but don’t panic: all you need is a little planning, self-awareness and research to get one step closer to making the right decision about where you should start learning to code. </span></p>
<p><b>In CodeBerry Programming School’s <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/category/basics-of-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">“Basics of Programming”</a> </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">series, we discuss programming-related topics and everything you need to know to get started. Stay tuned for new articles and find the answer to every “what”, “why”, and “how”, you may have had about coding!</span></p>
<h3>Basics of Programming</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/basics-of-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Basics of Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/a-brief-introduction-to-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">A Brief Introduction to Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/why-you-should-learn-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Why You Should Learn Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-much-can-you-make-as-a-programmer/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How much can you make as a programmer?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How to learn to code?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/which-programming-language-is-right-for-you/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Which programming language is good for you?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/how-long-it-takes-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How Long It Takes to Learn to Code</a></li>
<li><strong>How to find the right beginner programming course for you?</strong></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Would you like to learn how to code, online? Come and <a href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">try our first 25 lessons for free</a> at the CodeBerry Programming School.</span></p>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<h2></h2>
<h2 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ef5350;"><strong>Learn to code and change your career!</strong></span></h2>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 40px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12065" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>100% ONLINE</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12066" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-440x440.png 440w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4.png 512w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>IDEAL FOR BEGINNERS</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12067" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SUPPORTIVE COMMUNITY</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12068" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SELF-PACED LEARNING</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 10px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<h3 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #20c997;">Not sure if programming is for you? With CodeBerry you’ll like it.</span></h3>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 30px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-buttons aligncenter">
<div class="wp-block-button is-style-fill"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-white-color has-text-color has-background" style="border-radius: 10px; background-color: #ef5350;" href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><strong>TRY THE FIRST LESSONS FOR FREE</strong></a></div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 25px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12074" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png" sizes="(max-width: 282px) 100vw, 282px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png 564w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1-300x47.png 300w" alt="" width="282" height="45" /></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
