<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>CodeBerry Student Stories | CodeBerry Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/en/category/codeberry-student-stories/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog</link>
	<description>Learn programming online</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 11:33:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>You Can Learn Programming While Raising 3 Kids – The success Story of Our Student, Kriszta Klement</title>
		<link>/blog/en/learn-programming-while-raising-3-kids/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blog-admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 07:48:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[CodeBerry Student Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abacusan Studio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artec code learner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artec innovator academy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ArTec robot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coding stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how can i learn programming on my own]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how long does it take to learn programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learning programming kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming success stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[studuino artec]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[studuino software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[website]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://codeberryschool.com/blog/?p=7119</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kriszta Klement grew up in Orosháza, Hungary, where she graduated from high school with a specialization in hospitality. Shortly after graduation, she moved to the capital city of Budapest to find work as a waitress. When not working at the restaurant, Kriszta would take care of her 3 children during the evening and study programming [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kriszta Klement grew up in Orosháza, Hungary, where she graduated from high school with a specialization in hospitality. Shortly after graduation, she moved to the capital city of Budapest to find work as a waitress.</p>
<p>When not working at the restaurant, Kriszta would take care of her 3 children during the evening and study programming at night. Now, she teaches kids from 5 to 18 years old how to program robots at the Abacusan Studio.</p>
<p><strong><em>In our “CodeBerry Student Stories” series, we chat with students who have succeeded in finding a job as a developer.</p>
<p></em>I live here: </strong>Budapest, Hungary<br /><strong>I work here: </strong>Abacusan Studio<br /><strong>Time spent studying with <a class="rank-math-link" href="https://codeberryschool.com/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">CodeBerry</a>:</strong> about 10 months</p>
<p><strong>When asked about your job as a programmer, how do you usually respond?</p>
<p></strong>I teach programming—as an assistant member of a team—to children (ages 5–18) and to the educators working with them. In the case of children, our goal is to show them the fun side of coding and to pique their interest in the topic.</p>
<p>We would also like to eradicate digital illiteracy. By this, we mean that we want kids to grow beyond being mere users to getting involved in the creative side of the digital world. And in the case of educators, this means the extensive integration of robotics/programming into various subjects.</p>
<p>Rather than solely focusing on teachers of traditionally programming-related subjects, we put special emphasis on involving educators who teach history or literature.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12254 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>What did you do for a living before you started coding?</p>
<p></strong>I was the most enthusiastic waitress in the world. My job was my hobby—and the same is true of my current job. So, I could say that up until the age of 42, I still have never worked a day in my life, because I’ve always done things that I actually enjoy.</p>
<p>What I like most about my current job is the opportunity to always learn something new and develop myself personally. My favorite thing about my job is that whenever I learn something new, I can almost instantly share that new knowledge with others.</p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/6CuDy8CoyXMe2M-bYvLNoSE0wDJ9vomIhlcwXzgrSt1P4adPyZzCoxrFO4OYk6HQzwW4oWUmZH1MPrXnDuDZYEwqMcxNN53HzkANfSRd1NVDgDUszRgvzVCTTPXVt4CpEunRdh72" alt="This is the place where robot programming happens" /></figure>
<p class="has-text-align-center">Kriszta’s desk</p>
<p><strong>Why did you decide to start studying web development?</p>
<p></strong>To be honest, it was my 9-year-old and her friend who first took an interest in programming, which is how we got involved with Skool (a Hungarian organization offering free, innovative courses in technology to young girls).</p>
<p>The realization came to me about 1–1.5 years later, when I thought that maybe programming could be something that I should consider too. It had everything I was looking for in a new career: the option of working from home, being challenged, having flexible hours (you can make a lot of progress at night (: ), continuous development and learning, and new connections.</p>
<p>These are all things you can do when you’re retired. It seems like I had to catch up with the kids in digital literacy!</p>
<p><strong>How did you learn programming? Did you use any courses, books, or other materials in particular?</p>
<p></strong>I wouldn’t call myself a fully-fledged programmer. Rather, I’d prefer to say that I have learned the basics of programming and now use them daily with professional guidance and support. My first big encounter with the world of coding was through Dániel Pasztuhov’s email course on Java.</p>
<p>Then, I read Gusztáv Nagy’s book on web programming and received mentorship from him via Skype. As I have 3 children, my only option was to find a form of training that would be accessible from home.</p>
<p>What I liked the most about these courses, and CodeBerry in particular, is that you can also study and make progress at night, which gives you time to take care of the kids, run errands, and deal with other challenges during the day.</p>
<p>Studying at CodeBerry even allowed me to work a day job and take absolute control over the pace at which I progressed. I always got as much done as my time allowed.</p>
<p><strong>What did CodeBerry offer you? What was it like to study at our school?</p>
<p></strong>I really liked the personal mentorship. I always received quick help whenever I got stuck and I knew that I wasn’t alone. Most of the time, Amanda (my mentor) didn’t just give me a ready-made solution but also tried to guide me toward the answer to my problem by giving me hints so I could figure out the right code myself.</p>
<p>I loved how I could see both my progress and the next steps to take following each lesson. The virtual study group was also very active and that is where I found my other mentor, who also helped me a lot.</p>
<p>I really appreciate how everyone in this community is always eager to help, giving up their free time without regard for personal gain. Csaba Kapus has always answered my questions, too. He selflessly passed on huge amounts of practical knowledge to me, for which I would like to thank him again.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12018 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Do you have any experience, tips, or tricks to share with those who are just starting to learn programming?</p>
<p></strong>First of all, if coding has ever crossed your mind, you should definitely give it a shot. There are websites where you can learn some basic coding skills for free and get a taste of programming to see if it’s really for you or not.</p>
<p>Then, after having learned the basics, you can proceed to study programming in a more structured format (for example, in an online school such as this one). Many of the things I like about web programming were the same ones I did about waitressing: creativity and the opportunity to “serve”.</p>
<p>The “multiplier effect” of the acquired skills is also imperative. And it will stay important as long as the education system is sorely lacking the inclusion of this subject in the curriculum.</p>
<p>I do my best to convince the people around me to let children become more familiar with this area so that they are not just users in the digital world but also creators of games/apps.</p>
<p>Having daughters myself, I cannot stress enough how important these skills are for girls TOO! At first, it seems pretty far from fashion design, drawing, or any other creative profession preferred by girls. But I think web programming is just as creative—I speak from my own experience!</p>
<p><strong>Tell me a little about where you work now and what your duties are. What do you do during a typical day or week?</p>
<p></strong>It is said that being a parent is a real logistics challenge (languages, sports, music, competitions—times three) and it really is! I can make great use of these skills here.</p>
<p>My responsibilities at the Studio are very diverse. In addition to teaching kids how to use the Japanese <a class="rank-math-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jWuXSubP-mQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">ArTec robots,</a> I also manage and serve at the company’s online shop. In addition to assisting my bosses,</p>
<p>I also organize the storage room or clean when needed. I’m also responsible for the coordination and communication of the free, nationwide Abacusan-GE robotics program.</p>
<p>This profession provides many opportunities to do volunteer work, which both inspires me and gives new momentum to the team.</p>
<p>When we have a weekend event, I’m usually able to take the kids with me. During the week, as my presence is mostly requested in schools, I am in the office or in a given institution during the day.</p>
<p>And when one of my own kids needs me for something (a doctor’s appointment, school gets canceled, they just need to rest), we find a way for me to contribute from home at any time.</p>
<p><strong>Who do you work with and how do they help you with your job?</p>
<p></strong>I work with the two founders of the company: Sára Sugár and István Büti. They help me with both my personal and professional development by mentoring and supporting me. This helps me give one hundred percent at work without having to neglect my family.</p>
<p>I work on the actual (i.e. the robots) with my colleague, Balázs Szandavári. We do all the training and school programs as a team, with the four of us working together.</p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/iePUbixUuS-EzmQY-q7CcxV6hIJ5SFRK-bRfwmz4HCOpaPvVOsXOTa7QSk4APhcbEw-IqZsfhJDVza9xGZmIiHcXxZJhxcCS65Cwk3OSowEFj7JlOQ__EgPGjMlmYMnh173LF56z" alt="This is the place where robot programming happens" /></figure>
<p class="has-text-align-center">Our classroom</p>
<p><strong>What software, devices, and technology you are currently using?</p>
<p></strong>At the moment, I use the Japanese Studuino software, developed in cooperation by the American <a class="rank-math-link" href="https://www.mit.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">MIT</a> and the Japanese <a class="rank-math-link" href="https://www.artec-kk.co.jp/en/artecrobo-movie/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">ArTec</a> team. It is almost the same as Scratch, except it’s optimized for robots.</p>
<p>And this year, Studuino will be made compatible with Micro:bit too. Currently, these are the most widely accepted and the most efficient, user-friendly platforms in education on an international level.</p>
<p><strong>How long did you search for a job? Was it hard to find work?</p>
<p></strong>I’m one of the lucky ones who got a call asking whether or not they would be interested in a job if an opportunity opened up!</p>
<p>My children and I first visited Abacusan Studio when I had two days off of work and I gave them my phone number to get notifications about upcoming programs organized by them. Shortly after, they called to offer me a job. (:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12255 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Do you have any advice for those currently preparing for a job interview?</p>
<p></strong>My involvement in volunteer programs allows me to visit many multinational companies. And my experience is that motivated job seekers who are proficient in English and a regional European language are always welcome— even at the junior level—with the emphasis being on the regional European language.</p>
<p><strong>What is the next step for you? What direction are you taking?</p>
<p></strong>I’m currently working on the ArTec Innovator Academy introductions for small children. These introductions aim to get a younger generation engaged in coding, which so far has never been addressed in such a way in Hungary.</p>
<p>For this, I’ll also have to learn some new skills. Simultaneously, I work on the localization of a Japanese program based on our classroom experiences, with the guidance of Sára.</p>
<p><strong><em>In our “<a class="rank-math-link" href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/category/codeberry-student-stories/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">CodeBerry Student Stories” series </a>we chat with our students who succeeded in finding a job as a developer.<br /></em></strong></p>
<h3>Would you like to do the first steps on the way to become a site builder?</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/a-brief-introduction-to-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">A Brief Introduction to Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/why-you-should-learn-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Why You Should Learn Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-much-can-you-make-as-a-programmer/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How much can you make as a programmer?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/how-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How to learn to code?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/which-programming-language-is-right-for-you/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Which programming language is good for you?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-long-it-takes-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How Long It Takes to Learn to Code</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong><em><br />Would you like to learn how to code? Come and try our first 25 lessons for free at the </em></strong><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external"><strong><em>CodeBerry Programming School</em></strong></a><strong><em>.</em></strong></p>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<h2></h2>
<h2 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ef5350;"><strong>Learn to code and change your career!</strong></span></h2>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 40px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12065" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>100% ONLINE</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12066" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-440x440.png 440w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4.png 512w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>IDEAL FOR BEGINNERS</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12067" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SUPPORTIVE COMMUNITY</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12068" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SELF-PACED LEARNING</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 10px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<h3 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #20c997;">Not sure if programming is for you? With CodeBerry you’ll like it.</span></h3>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 30px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-buttons aligncenter">
<div class="wp-block-button is-style-fill"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-white-color has-text-color has-background" style="border-radius: 10px; background-color: #ef5350;" href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><strong>TRY THE FIRST LESSONS FOR FREE</strong></a></div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 25px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12074" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png" sizes="(max-width: 282px) 100vw, 282px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png 564w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1-300x47.png 300w" alt="" width="282" height="45" /></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Personal Trainer to FrontEnd Developer – The Story of Our Student, Gábor Baranyi</title>
		<link>/blog/en/frontend-developer-gabor-baranyi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blog-admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 11:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[CodeBerry Student Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baranyi gábor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[front end developer school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[front-end]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HTML]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intellij for students]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intellij student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internal project]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Javascript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[javascript trainer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[profession szeged]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programmer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[student intellij]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[webstorm student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[webstorm student version]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://codeberryschool.com/blog/?p=6604</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Gábor Baranyi used to work as a personal trainer, and also held training sessions for groups at a gym. Since then, he has found something that fulfils him, and where he can develop continuously: he is working as a junior frontend developer at a medium-sized company. I live here: Szeged, Hungary I work here: Minero [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b>Gábor Baranyi</b> <span style="font-weight: 400;">used to work as a personal trainer, and also held training sessions for groups at a gym. Since then, he has found something that fulfils him, and where he can develop continuously: he is working as a junior frontend developer at a medium-sized company</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><b>I live here:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Szeged, Hungary</span></p>
<p><b>I work here:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Minero IT Hungary KFT.</span></p>
<p><b>Time spent studying with CodeBerry</b><b>:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> 10 months</span></p>
<p><b>I work with:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Fujitsu Lifebook A555, Windows 7, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IntelliJ_IDEA" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">IntelliJ</a>, <a href="https://www.sourcetreeapp.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">SourceTree</a></span></p>
<p><b>When you’re asked about your profession, how do you answer?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It depends on who’s asking.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> If it is a professional in the field, I say a frontend developer. If it is a layperson showing some interest, my answer is that I am a programmer or software developer</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><b>What did you do for a living before you switched to web development?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I used to work full time as a personal trainer and held group training sessions at a functional gym. I still offer these group sessions, in addition to working as a programmer.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12254 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p><b>Why did you decide to start learning web development?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">have </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">always been interested in web design, in how and why a website looks as it does. Besides that, the gym&#8217;s webpage was partly managed by us, trainers, so I spent a lot of time writing and designing our WordPress blog, which I really enjoyed. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I spotted a good opportunity on Facebook, where they advertised an online web develop</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ment</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> course. I looked it up, and I knew that I have to master the ins and outs of this profession on this platform&#8230; or at least the basics of it. It was the advertisement of CodeBerry.</span></p>
<p><b>How did you learn programming? What kind of courses, books etc. did you use?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After seeing the above-mentioned advertisement, I started to study at CodeBerry&#8217;s online course in September 2016, and later I added Codecademy and Udemy courses to my learning resources as well. I searched for and learned specific programming languages on video sharing sites.</span></p>
<p><b>What did CodeBerry offer you? What was it like to study at our school?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It was very useful. I really liked your monthly subscription system, because this way I could study at my own pace. I loved the explanations, the examples through which the tasks are presented.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-6606 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Gabor_Baranyi_pic1.jpeg" alt="This is how a frontend developer’s desk looks like" width="760" height="427" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Gabor_Baranyi_pic1.jpeg 760w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Gabor_Baranyi_pic1-300x169.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 760px) 100vw, 760px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gábor’s Desk</span></p>
<p><b>Do you have any experience, tips or tricks to share with those who are just starting their studies?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I find it very important to learn the basics well and to revise the earlier lessons to see the connections </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">and to be able to put the new material in context. Revision is crucial.</span></p>
<p><b>Tell me a little about where you work now, what your duties are. What do you do on a typical day or week?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Currently, I work at a Budapest based company&#8217;s office in Szeged. We are developing an internal project where I deal with the frontend, consisting of <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/a-brief-introduction-to-web-development/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.</a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I arrive at the office around 8 a.m. and I leave at 5 p.m. I try to do something different when I am not there; training or holding group training, so I can </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">face the next working day energized and refreshed.</span></p>
<p><b>Who do you work with, and how do they help your work?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are currently about 20 people working in the office. I have a mentor helping me with my progress, who also supervises the project we are working on.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12018 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p><b>What kind of software, tools or technologies do you work with currently?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The development environment is IntelliJ, for version control we use SourceTree and for repo, we use BitBucket.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the project, we use HTML, CSS (SCSS), jQuery, Angular JS, Angular Material and FUSE.</span></p>
<p><b>How long were you looking for a job? Was it hard to find a place to work?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Actually, I was still studying when my friend suggest</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ed that I s</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">end my CV to the company he works for. They invited me for an int</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">erview, and a few weeks later they called me saying that they would like to work with me, based on my performance.</span></p>
<p><b>How was the interview process?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After a brief introduction of the company, the interview continued in English, and it was my turn to introduce myself, talk a bit about my private life and about how and where I learned programming, also in English.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This was followed by a technical part, where they assessed my knowledge and gave me a few logic tests to solve.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The whole interview took about an hour.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12255 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p><b>Do you have any advice for those who are currently preparing for a job interview?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is very important that everything you say has to be positive. Even if something negative comes up, try to talk about it from a positive aspect or perspective. Always stay confident, and show that you are able and willing to improve in any field.</span></p>
<p><b>What is the next step for you? What direction are you taking?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I want to know as much about frontend development as possible and get a taste of backend development as well to see and understand the whole background process.</span></p>
<p><b><i>In our <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/category/codeberry-student-stories/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">“CodeBerry Student Stories” series</a> we chat with our students who succeeded in finding a job as a developer.</i></b></p>
<h3>Would you like to do the first steps on the way to become a site builder?</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/a-brief-introduction-to-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">A Brief Introduction to Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/why-you-should-learn-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Why You Should Learn Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-much-can-you-make-as-a-programmer/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How much can you make as a programmer?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/how-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How to learn to code?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/which-programming-language-is-right-for-you/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Which programming language is good for you?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-long-it-takes-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How Long It Takes to Learn to Code</a></li>
</ul>
<p><b><i>Would you like to learn how to code? Come and try our first 25 lessons for free at the </i></b><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external"><b><i>CodeBerry Programming School</i></b></a><b><i>.</i></b></p>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<h2></h2>
<h2 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ef5350;"><strong>Learn to code and change your career!</strong></span></h2>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 40px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12065" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>100% ONLINE</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12066" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-440x440.png 440w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4.png 512w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>IDEAL FOR BEGINNERS</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12067" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SUPPORTIVE COMMUNITY</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12068" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SELF-PACED LEARNING</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 10px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<h3 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #20c997;">Not sure if programming is for you? With CodeBerry you’ll like it.</span></h3>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 30px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-buttons aligncenter">
<div class="wp-block-button is-style-fill"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-white-color has-text-color has-background" style="border-radius: 10px; background-color: #ef5350;" href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><strong>TRY THE FIRST LESSONS FOR FREE</strong></a></div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 25px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12074" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png" sizes="(max-width: 282px) 100vw, 282px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png 564w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1-300x47.png 300w" alt="" width="282" height="45" /></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>JavaScript Developer with a Social Worker Degree – The  Success Story of Our Student, Anikó Borosová</title>
		<link>/blog/en/javascript-developer-aniko-borosova/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blog-admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 11:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[CodeBerry Student Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[degree in javascript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EDMdesigner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[javascript degree]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[javascript developer blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[javascript mentor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[javascript story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[javascript worker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self taught javascript developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-taught programmer success stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sublime text student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[worker in javascript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[worker javascript]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://codeberryschool.com/blog/?p=6576</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Anikó Borosová got a degree in social work from the Eötvös Loránd University. After graduation, she worked in the social sector, then as a data processor and in customer service. Currently, she is working as a junior JavaScript developer at EDMdesigner.com. I live here: Budapest, Hungary I work here: EDMdesigner.com Kft. Time spent studying with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b>Anikó Borosová</b> <span style="font-weight: 400;">got a degree in social work from the Eötvös Loránd University. After graduation, she worked in the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">social sector</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, then as a data processor and in customer service. Currently, she is working as a junior JavaScript developer at </span><a href="https://edmdesigner.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">EDMdesigner.com</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><b>I live here:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Budapest, Hungary</span></p>
<p><b>I work here:</b> <a href="http://edmdesigner.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">EDMdesigner.com</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Kft.</span></p>
<p><b>Time spent studying with <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">CodeBerry</a></b><b>:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> 4 months</span></p>
<p><b>I work with:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> ASUS laptop with Ubuntu at work / Lenovo ThinkPad Edge running Windows 10 at home / <a href="https://www.sublimetext.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">Sublime Text</a> / I have an 11-year-old Nokia (no, not the 3310, I’m not that cool)</span></p>
<h4>When you’re asked about your profession, how do you answer?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I say programmer or <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/beginners-guide-to-javascript/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">junior JavaScript developer</a>. There aren&#8217;t any programmers or self-taught gurus around me, so I don&#8217;t usually go into details. Moreover, this is a more difficult question than</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> it seems</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to be at first. I am not a social worker anymore, but I don&#8217;t feel like a programmer yet either, it hasn&#8217;t become a part of my identity so far. It&#8217;s a weird feeling.</span></p>
<h4>What had been your job before you started coding?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After graduating as a social worker from the Eötvös Loránd University, I returned to Slovakia and started working in my field. I worked at a jobcentre and for the local government, mostly with the unemployed and socially disadvantaged clients, the homeless and a segregated Romani district. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Later I worked in data processing/customer service positions in the automobile industry.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12254 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h4>Why did you decide to start learning web development?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My previous jobs didn’t make me happy. As a social worker you hardly ever see the fruits of your efforts: Our resources and time are usually only enough for band-aid solutions, and there is only a minimal chance to achieve real change. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s like a Kafka novel: You go marching against the system, trying to help, but without adequate resources, or in a burnt-out, demotivating environment, that is more often than not, just keeps humiliating the client, you quickly lose hope, and then it’s up to you to decide whether you flee or get chewed up by the system. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I decided to flee, but working in the IT sector never occurred to me as a viable option. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Then last year I heard a lot about the ever-growing demand for developers, and all the online courses, so I decided to try one. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I liked it, and most importantly: I could see the results of my work. I improved slowly but steadily, and a couple of months later I thought to myself: It&#8217;s about time I take this more seriously, as it might actually lead to a job. And it did.</span></p>
<h4>How did you learn programming? What kind of courses, books etc. did you use?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I started at <a href="https://www.codecademy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">Codecademy</a> and <a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">FreeCodeCamp</a>, reading documentations, following video streams on the side, then I started studying with <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">CodeBerry</a>. I also attended the Bratislava workshop of <a href="http://railsgirls.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">Rails Girls</a> this summer.</span></p>
<h4>What did CodeBerry offer you? What was it like to study at our school?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Having a mentor was the greatest help for me, it proved to be the most efficient way of studying. Before CodeBerry, I used to study on my own, but that way — especially as a beginner — you can&#8217;t be sure you understand the connections and the logic properly; it&#8217;s hard to figure out what&#8217;s missing and what should be your next step. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At CodeBerry, mentorship was really effective and informal. You can ask for help anytime you reach an obstacle, and get an answer fairly quickly; even when you have 10 questions at once. This was a really positive experience compared to my earlier studies in the traditional educational system.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I also made great use of your help with </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">the preparation for the interviews. I received tips on what questions I should expect and how to respond to them. This extra knowledge helped me a lot, especially as I was switching from another profession, starting from zero in this field.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12018 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h4>Do you have any experience, tips or tricks to share with those who are just starting their studies?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It doesn&#8217;t matter if you don&#8217;t understand something at first (or second, third, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">umpteenth</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">) glance, just keep trying. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Keep at it until you succeed.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Keep looking at it until you start to see it (the advice of my high school teacher — and it is so true). There will always be obstacles, but that is no reason to give up.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ask for help, dare to ask questions, and if you find yourself home alone, stuck without answers and motivation, then simply attend an IRL (&#8220;in real life&#8221;, i.e. personal) programming event or workshop to meet and talk to other people who are in the same boat. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Rail Girls gave me a great push at the perfect moment, leaving me with a really good feeling. I returned from the workshop thinking that if my mentor (my hero, Pilar Huidobro), who also started programming at a similar event, could work as a software developer and teacher after 5 years of coding, then I can do it too, I can learn it too.</span></p>
<h4>Tell me a little about where you work now, what your duties are. What do you do on a typical day or week?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I work at </span><a href="http://edmdesigner.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><span style="font-weight: 400;">EDMdesigner</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as a JavaScript developer. We are working on the company&#8217;s e-mail content management software in smaller teams, where everyone gets his or her part of the work. Apart from this, we have a constantly growing component library for Knockouts.js, the Knob.js — I also made a new component for this. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My team&#8217;s (well, duo&#8217;s) task is user acquisition; we are working on finding out how we can achieve more registrations and subscribers. We use Google Analytics, Intercom and Hotjar.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Following the<a href="https://www.scrumguides.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"> SCRUM-method</a>, we have stand-ups every morning, where we talk about the daily tasks, obstacles and future tasks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite the difficulty, it proved to be an advantage that I had to write code from day one.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> This way I get to learn the company&#8217;s workflow on the go, and I can find out how my code meshes with the already existing one, done by my coworkers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">During the past 6 weeks, I&#8217;ve only done things </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I had never done before, so I actually learn new things every day.</span></p>
<h4>Who do you work with, and how do they help your work?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is not a big company, we barely count 20 people in the office. Most colleagues are working part-time, and we also have students among us. During the stand-ups, which I mentioned before, we also talk about how I&#8217;m supposed to proceed and I can ask anybody if I&#8217;m stuck, everyone is really helpful.</span></p>
<p><div id="attachment_6578" style="width: 753px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-6578" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-6578 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Aniko_Borosova_pic1.jpeg" alt="This is the office where Anikó works as a javascript developer" width="743" height="557" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Aniko_Borosova_pic1.jpeg 743w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Aniko_Borosova_pic1-300x225.jpeg 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Aniko_Borosova_pic1-510x382.jpeg 510w" sizes="(max-width: 743px) 100vw, 743px" /><p id="caption-attachment-6578" class="wp-caption-text">My current workplace</p></div></p>
<h4>What software, devices and technologies do you work with currently?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I use Ubuntu, Slack, Sublime Text, terminator, GitKraken, Node.js, Jasmine, gulp, MongoDB, Redis, Docker, Nginx etc. There are also new JavaScript libraries and npm packages published daily or weekly.</span></p>
<h4>How long were you looking for a job? Was it hard to find a place to work?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My case can&#8217;t be called typical, as it took quite a bit of luck that things turned out as they did. My strategy was to apply for at least 8–10 jobs, struggle a bit at first trying to get through the interviews, but get the hang of it by the end. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I was hoping that the 10th interview or so would be successful, and they would finally offer me a job. Instead, EDMdesigner was the first place I contacted, and they were the ones who hired me. Don&#8217;t forget though, that it&#8217;s one thing to get the job, and another to be able to keep it. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I was in a total panic after the interviews, feeling I wasn&#8217;t prepared for this and that it wasn&#8217;t what I had planned. The first weeks were the most difficult, I was afraid that I won&#8217;t fit in, that I&#8217;m incapable of doing my tasks. Since then, 6 weeks have passed, and I&#8217;m still standing.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12255 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h4>How was the interview process?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There were three stages in 1–1.5 weeks. The first one was a phone interview, where they asked questions about JavaScript. After that, I had about 3 days to create a &#8220;to-do list&#8221; using JavaScript, including the HTML code. And finally, we had a Skype interview, discussing the workplace, daily tasks, the team and the job requirements.</span></p>
<h4>Do you have any advice for those who are currently preparing for a job interview?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Don&#8217;t be too nervous about it. Get enough sleep the night before. Definitely more than 2.5 hours. This is very important!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And don&#8217;t panic if you actually get the job. It will all work out.</span></p>
<h4>What is the next step for you? What direction are you taking?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&#8217;s hard to see the future – currently, there&#8217;s so much new information, that I&#8217;m happy if I manage to plan even a few days ahead. What is certain is that I still have to learn a lot of new things and tools, </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I have to improve to &#8220;level up&#8221; and be able to work more independently. I am far from being a master of JavaScript, but I hope I will get there one day.</span></p>
<p><b><i>In our <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/category/codeberry-student-stories/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">“CodeBerry Student Stories” series</a> we chat with our students who succeeded in finding a job as a developer.</i></b></p>
<h3>Would you like to do the first steps on the way to become a site builder?</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/a-brief-introduction-to-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">A Brief Introduction to Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/why-you-should-learn-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Why You Should Learn Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-much-can-you-make-as-a-programmer/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How much can you make as a programmer?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/how-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How to learn to code?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/which-programming-language-is-right-for-you/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Which programming language is good for you?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-long-it-takes-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How Long It Takes to Learn to Code</a></li>
</ul>
<p><b><i>Would you like to learn how to code? Come and try our first 25 lessons for free at the </i></b><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external"><b><i>CodeBerry Programming School</i></b></a><b>.</b></p>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<h2></h2>
<h2 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ef5350;"><strong>Learn to code and change your career!</strong></span></h2>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 40px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12065" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>100% ONLINE</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12066" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-440x440.png 440w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4.png 512w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>IDEAL FOR BEGINNERS</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12067" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SUPPORTIVE COMMUNITY</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12068" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SELF-PACED LEARNING</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 10px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<h3 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #20c997;">Not sure if programming is for you? With CodeBerry you’ll like it.</span></h3>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 30px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-buttons aligncenter">
<div class="wp-block-button is-style-fill"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-white-color has-text-color has-background" style="border-radius: 10px; background-color: #ef5350;" href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><strong>TRY THE FIRST LESSONS FOR FREE</strong></a></div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 25px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12074" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png" sizes="(max-width: 282px) 100vw, 282px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png 564w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1-300x47.png 300w" alt="" width="282" height="45" /></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The story of our student, Balázs Gergely Soós &#8211; I needed some peace and quiet</title>
		<link>/blog/en/story-our-student-balazs-gergely-soos/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blog-admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 08:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[CodeBerry Student Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Balázs Gergely Soós]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BASIC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BME]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Budapest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[C++]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer science engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hungary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[morgan stanley my desk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MorganStanley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[my desk morgan stanley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[my desktop morgan stanley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[senior developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streamnovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SZTAKI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zinemath]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://codeberryschool.com/?p=5313</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Balázs Gergely Soós, BeeGee is a graduate computer science engineer with a PhD from the PPKE Multidisciplinary Doctoral School of Sciences and Technology, also an alumni member of the BME Schönherz College &#8211; and now also a student of CodeBerry. He formerly worked for SZTAKI as a research assistant, was a research engineer at Searchlab, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Balázs Gergely Soós</strong>, BeeGee is a graduate computer science engineer with a PhD from the PPKE Multidisciplinary Doctoral School of Sciences and Technology, also an alumni member of the BME Schönherz College &#8211; and now also a student of <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">CodeBerry</a>. He formerly worked for SZTAKI as a research assistant, was a research engineer at Searchlab, senior developer and founder of Streamnovation and leader programmer at Zinemath.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>I live here</strong>: Budapest, Hungary</p>
<p><strong>I work here</strong>: MorganStanley</p>
<p><strong>Time spent studying with <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">CodeBerry</a></strong>: 3 months</p>
<p><strong>I work with</strong>:HP ENVY, Samsung Galaxy S4 mini, Chrome, <a href="https://notepad-plus-plus.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">Notepad++</a>, <a href="https://www.atlassian.com/git/tutorials/gitk" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">gitk</a></p>
</blockquote>
<h4>When you&#8217;re asked about your profession, how do you answer?</h4>
<p>I’m a software developer.</p>
<h4>What was your job before you started coding? Did you have any former experience in this field?</h4>
<p>When I was a child I used to look for swapped O’s and zeros in BASIC programs. I gave up an aircraft modelling workshop to draw with a Commodore+4 and I was often fiddling with GV-Basic (C64) too. I used Tubo Pascal in high school and <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/beginners-guide-to-c/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">C++</a> at university among other interesting languages. <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/beginners-guide-to-c/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">C++</a> stuck with me for quite a long time… and then machine vision, robotics and GPU programming came along.</p>
<h4>Why did you decide to start learning web development?</h4>
<p>In my opinion desktop applications are done for. Instead, I was interested in mobile development and cloud services. I wanted to learn WebGL after coming across it for the first time. I thought the first step should be recalling my web knowledge, as I had previously dealt with some <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/beginners-guide-to-php/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">PHP</a> and MySQL, but the frontend was always done by someone else. Many of my projects focused on calculation, not the interface. However, I became curious about the tricks done by <a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/g/gui.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">GUI wizards</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12254 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h4>Please tell us more about what you do now, what tasks you have? What happens on a typical day?</h4>
<p>I work in a bank, so that’s a secret. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> But my job includes some daily frontend tasks.</p>
<h4>How long were you looking for a job? How did you land your current position?</h4>
<p>My previous one was like a dream job: a real dreamer mastermind, fantastic engineers, international exhibitions and a rock-solid investor. But one day I felt like it was all too much. I needed some peace and quiet to be able to hear some new voices and finally have time for my family and myself.</p>
<p>This impulse hit me in the summer. My wife had 4 weeks off, so we moved to Venice for the time. Relaxing by the lakeside made me realise how much I’m missing some intellectual activity, so I started studying…</p>
<p>Two months later I had a couple of interviews. When the news of me not working got around, one of my dorm fellows called me and said if I still love those special program languages and I’m interested in big databases, then he has an empty desk for me by his side…</p>
<h4>How did you learn programming? What kind of courses, books etc. did you use?</h4>
<p>I don’t remember anymore, it just happened. I possessed a few issues with Computerbooks. The next thing was university: György Pongor and Zoltán László. After that, I kept to online materials.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-8548" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/home-office-336373_1920-1-1024x683.jpg" alt="As a Codeberry student you can learn everywhere" width="1024" height="683" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/home-office-336373_1920-1-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/home-office-336373_1920-1-300x200.jpg 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/home-office-336373_1920-1-768x512.jpg 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/home-office-336373_1920-1-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/home-office-336373_1920-1-1080x720.jpg 1080w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/home-office-336373_1920-1.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<h4>&#8220;What did CodeBerry offer you? What was it like to study at our school?</h4>
<p>I read about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Node.js" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">Node.js</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Angular_(web_framework)" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">Angular</a> and could feel the power of their combination. During my doctorate years, I fell in love with independent research, the joy of discovering something new. On the other hand, I do respect teachers who gave me a good kickstart before the journey. Learning out of blogs is really like being in a big city without a map: there are dozens of buses, many tramlines and a few undergrounds. Sometimes you need help with the directions if you actually want to get somewhere.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/andras-p-toth-serial-entrepreneur/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Andris</a> and I meet each other every month. He told me about CodeBerry when it was just a twinkle in his eye. Later <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/web-development-story-of-arpad-binecz/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Bini</a> said he likes the idea. I thought: why not? I was probably one of the first twenty applicants. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>Before it wasn’t my job to make something pretty. At the beginning of the lessons, the focus was on the frontend. I didn’t regret that though. It was very useful to be able to try everything I just learned and test my knowledge with quizzes. By the time I completed a WordPress site, CSS and I became great friends.</p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12255 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h4>Do you have any experience, tips or tricks to share with those who are just starting their studies?</h4>
<p>You just have to sit down and do it… I got the final push from a friend of mine: he asked me to create a responsive website for him. He took advantage of me not working at the time. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<h4>What is the next step for you? What direction are you taking?</h4>
<p>As soon as I&#8217;ll have a few spare weekends, I&#8217;ll steer back to my original goal, WebGL. Maybe Spiced up with some VR.</p>
<p><strong><em>In our &#8220;<a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/category/codeberry-student-stories/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">CodeBerry Student Stories&#8221; series</a> we chat with our students who succeeded in finding a job as a developer.</em></strong></p>
<h3>Would you like to do the first steps on the way to become a site builder?</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/a-brief-introduction-to-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">A Brief Introduction to Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/why-you-should-learn-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Why You Should Learn Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-much-can-you-make-as-a-programmer/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How much can you make as a programmer?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/how-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How to learn to code?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/which-programming-language-is-right-for-you/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Which programming language is good for you?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-long-it-takes-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How Long It Takes to Learn to Code</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong><em>Would you like to learn how to code? Come and try our <a href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">first lessons for free at the CodeBerry Programming School.</a></em></strong></p>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<h2></h2>
<h2 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ef5350;"><strong>Learn to code and change your career!</strong></span></h2>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 40px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12065" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>100% ONLINE</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12066" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-440x440.png 440w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4.png 512w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>IDEAL FOR BEGINNERS</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12067" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SUPPORTIVE COMMUNITY</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12068" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SELF-PACED LEARNING</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 10px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<h3 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #20c997;">Not sure if programming is for you? With CodeBerry you’ll like it.</span></h3>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 30px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-buttons aligncenter">
<div class="wp-block-button is-style-fill"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-white-color has-text-color has-background" style="border-radius: 10px; background-color: #ef5350;" href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><strong>TRY THE FIRST LESSONS FOR FREE</strong></a></div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 25px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12074" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png" sizes="(max-width: 282px) 100vw, 282px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png 564w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1-300x47.png 300w" alt="" width="282" height="45" /></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Becoming a frontend developer from a bakery – János Farkas&#8217;s story</title>
		<link>/blog/en/becoming-a-frontend-developer/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blog-admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 07:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[CodeBerry Student Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[being a front end developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bootstrap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CodeBerry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[codeberry indonesia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[codeberry school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[front end developer blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[front end developer school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frontend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frontend blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frontend developer blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[git]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HTML]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hungary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Javascript/jQuery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Node/Bower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PHP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phpstorm student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SCSS/LESS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web development hungary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y-collective]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://codeberryschool.com/?p=5204</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[János Farkas is a construction technician, an applied graphic artist and a baker by profession. He has been working as a junior frontend developer at Y-collective (a Hungarian company) since January. In this episode of Student Stories, let us take you on a follow-up journey with a former CodeBerry Programming School student. I live here: [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>János Farkas</strong> is a construction technician, an applied graphic artist and a baker by profession.<br />
He has been working as a junior frontend developer at Y-collective (a Hungarian company) since January.</p>
<p><strong>In this episode of <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/category/codeberry-student-stories/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Student Stories</a>, let us take you on a follow-up journey</strong> with a former CodeBerry Programming School student.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>I live here</strong>: Pécs, Hungary</p>
<p><strong>I work here</strong>: <a href="https://y-collective.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">Y-collective</a></p>
<p><strong>I studied at CodeBerry for this long</strong>: 2 months</p>
<p><strong>I use</strong>: PHPStorm, Stack Overflow, CSS-tricks, W3Schools</p>
</blockquote>
<h3><strong>When you&#8217;re asked about your profession, how do you answer?</strong></h3>
<p>First of all, I say that I am a programmer, usually everyone understands this.<br />
In most cases, people are interested when I tell them my profession. So, I give more details by explaining that I prepare the user interface of web pages visible to users.<br />
Sometimes I work on server-side scripting too&#8230;</p>
<h3><strong>What did you do for a living before you switched to web development?</strong></h3>
<p>This is the first time I work as a website developer. However, I started to get familiar with this field much earlier.<br />
I&#8217;ve been interested in this field for the past 10 years, but I only started taking it seriously last year.<br />
So far I only created some smaller websites (and I would do these in a different way now <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> ).<br />
As for my previous jobs, I worked in the trading sector for 10 years.<br />
As the manager of the bakery department of a 7000 square meter superstore, my task was to supervise production, procurement, schedules and anything related.<br />
So, it was quite a big change for me.</p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12254 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h3><strong>Why did you decide to start studying web development?</strong></h3>
<p>I have always been fascinated by the software part of computer science.<br />
Each year, the internet and web-related technologies play a greater and greater role in our everyday life.<br />
This results in an urging need for more and more professional developers. I would like to take this chance. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<h3><strong>Tell me a little about where you work now, what your duties are. What do you do on a typical day or week?</strong></h3>
<p>I work as a junior site builder at Y-collective. Our office is in downtown Pécs.<br />
At the beginning of the week, there is a project management meeting where the tasks are determined and assigned. So it is more or less clear what everyone is going to work on during the week and maybe the following week.<br />
We have a lot of projects, so we have quite a variety of tasks.<br />
And it may happen that some urgent matter or a bug comes up on an ad hoc basis.<br />
My days usually start around 6 a.m., with a coffee.<br />
While drinking it, I glance over the news or I read about something I was dealing with the previous day.<br />
I usually go to work by bike. The official working hours are from eight in the morning to four in the afternoon, plus at times I stay a half-hour or an hour longer.<br />
Besides developments we do changes, bug fixes, importing existing modules to other projects, administrative duties, database modification&#8230;<br />
We recently started to concentrate more on unique WordPress developments.<br />
At times it needs some research or a plugin change, so it&#8217;s not boring.<br />
What I use daily is PHP, HTML, CSS, SCSS/LESS, Javascript/jQuery, Node/Bower, Bootstrap, and git.<br />
There are weekly/biweekly internal training and meetups on some subject.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-5833 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Janos_Farkas_pic1-3.jpeg" alt="This is, how János’s workplace looks like as a junior frontend developer." width="800" height="543" /></p>
<h3><strong>How long were you looking for a job? Was it hard to find a place to work?</strong></h3>
<p>After all, I wasn&#8217;t looking for a job for long. Or rather, I did not expect to be able to enter the world of IT within such a short period of time.<br />
<a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/im-adam-freisinger-the-founder-of-codeberry-and-this-is-how-i-work/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Adam Freisinger</a>, one of the mentors at CodeBerry asked me about my professional goals, as I was making good progress with the materials.<br />
I didn&#8217;t keep it a secret that I intended to work in this field, so he organized an interview for me, then I got a trial task, and later a job.<br />
Hereby I&#8217;d like to thank everyone for the support, I&#8217;ll do my best to make up for it <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<h3><strong>How did you learn programming? What kind of courses, books etc. did you use?</strong></h3>
<p>At first, I researched online materials, read articles and did tutorials.<br />
Then there was even more self-studying and then the next step was CodeBerry.</p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12018 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h3><strong>What did CodeBerry offer you? What was it like to study at our school?</strong></h3>
<p>I was looking for an online course that could help me get to the next level. But for various reasons, none of them seemed really good.<br />
Then I stumbled upon CodeBerry.<br />
I really liked the approach: they not only realized that individuals need this course, but also that the IT sector is in need of junior professionals.<br />
A symbiotic relationship is built from this approach, which serves everyone&#8217;s needs.<br />
Studying is completely personalized: everyone can progress at their own pace. If someone is stuck, help is available from the Slack community, and Amanda.<br />
I wouldn&#8217;t say that I found very many new pieces of information in the teaching material, but for me, it was very useful for revising, for filling in the gaps I had, for deepening my knowledge&#8230;<br />
Personally, the extra service CodeBerry provided me was that I could assess my knowledge quite well, so I was more confident to make the decision to try myself out.</p>
<h3><strong>Do you have any experience, tips or tricks to share with those who are just starting their studies?</strong></h3>
<p>Start a side project while studying. Give a solution to a real problem, no matter how small it may be.<br />
You can learn a lot this way.<br />
Feel free to copy a solution or parts of it, but plan your own version and analyze and understand the parts that are not obvious to you.<br />
Even the scope of your studies can be built on this.</p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12255 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h3><strong>What is the next step for you? What direction are you taking?</strong></h3>
<p>First of all, I definitely want to deepen my knowledge and catch up with my colleagues.<br />
We have a very well-prepared and seasoned team. Everyone is really good at what they do, and I learn a lot from them every day.<br />
Then I want to reach my own limits, and then&#8230; we&#8217;ll see.</p>
<p><strong><em>In our &#8220;CodeBerry Student Stories&#8221; series we chat with our students who succeeded in finding a job as a developer.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Would you like to learn how to code? Come and <a href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" data-wplink-edit="true" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">try our first lessons for free at the CodeBerry Programming School.</a></em></strong></p>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<h2></h2>
<h2 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ef5350;"><strong>Learn to code and change your career!</strong></span></h2>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 40px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12065" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>100% ONLINE</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12066" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-440x440.png 440w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4.png 512w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>IDEAL FOR BEGINNERS</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12067" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SUPPORTIVE COMMUNITY</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12068" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SELF-PACED LEARNING</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 10px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<h3 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #20c997;">Not sure if programming is for you? With CodeBerry you’ll like it.</span></h3>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 30px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-buttons aligncenter">
<div class="wp-block-button is-style-fill"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-white-color has-text-color has-background" style="border-radius: 10px; background-color: #ef5350;" href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><strong>TRY THE FIRST LESSONS FOR FREE</strong></a></div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 25px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12074" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png" sizes="(max-width: 282px) 100vw, 282px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png 564w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1-300x47.png 300w" alt="" width="282" height="45" /></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>From agricultural engineer to sitebuilder – the story of our student Márton Radnóczi</title>
		<link>/blog/en/from-agricultural-engineer-sitebuilder/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blog-admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 08:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[CodeBerry Student Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apertus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Budapest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CodeBerry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[codeberry ltd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hungary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[php storm student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phpstorm for student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phpstorm for students]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phpstorm free student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phpstorm student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sitebuilder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[webstorm for students]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[webstorm student]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://codeberryschool.com/?p=5322</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Márton Radnóczi, Marci is an agronomist specialised in rural development. He&#8217;s been passionate about web and mobile related products from day one, finally last year he decided to devote more time to them. He now works at Apertus Ltd. as a sitebuilder. I live here: Budapest, Hungary I work here: Apertus Ltd. Time spent studying [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Márton Radnóczi</strong>, Marci is an agronomist specialised in rural development. He&#8217;s been passionate about web and mobile related products from day one, finally last year he decided to devote more time to them. He now works at Apertus Ltd. as a sitebuilder.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>I live here:</strong> Budapest, Hungary</p>
<p><strong>I work here:</strong> Apertus Ltd.</p>
<p><strong>Time spent studying with CodeBerry:</strong> 6 months</p>
<p><strong>I work with:</strong> Oneplus One, <a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/phpstorm/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">PhpStorm</a>, Adobe*</p>
</blockquote>
<h3><strong>When you&#8217;re asked about your profession, how do you answer?</strong></h3>
<p>Briefly: I’m a site builder or web developer. I build websites without a function. My task is to convert sketches into code, so the desired design appears in the browser.</p>
<h3><strong>What did you do for a living before you started coding? Did you have any relevant experience in this field?</strong></h3>
<p>I worked in finance before I became a project manager in a startup. I&#8217;ve never learned to code, I just had an idea of how things worked and what logic they followed.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12018 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><strong>Why did you decide to start <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/a-brief-introduction-to-web-development/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">studying web development</a>?</strong></h3>
<p>It always appealed to me as a hobby. Time flew by when I started digging into related topics, I felt unstoppable. It was an unmistakable flow experience I&#8217;ve never experienced before during work. I liked the thought of doing this full-time. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<h3><strong>Tell me a little about where you work now, what your duties are. What do you do on a typical day or week?</strong></h3>
<p>We develop various size web systems at Apertus Ltd. As a site builder, my role is to create a static page out of a specified design or just simple sketches. Most of the time I get a few pictures that guide my code. I work on numerous projects simultaneously, but normally I focus on just one each day.</p>
<h3><strong>How long were you looking for a job? Was it hard to find a place to work?</strong></h3>
<p>I searched for 1 week, so I admit it was surprisingly easy. I suspected it would be fast, but not this fast though.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-8199" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/programming-2480671_1920-1024x683.jpg" alt="Never too late to build a career as a sitebuilder" width="1024" height="683" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/programming-2480671_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/programming-2480671_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/programming-2480671_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/programming-2480671_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/programming-2480671_1920-1080x720.jpg 1080w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/programming-2480671_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></strong></p>
<h3><strong>How did you learn programming? What kind of courses, books etc. did you use?</strong></h3>
<p>I only enrolled in online courses. First, I tested myself on free materials and then I paid for two that complemented each other. I also watched tutorials on Youtube to gain a deeper insight into some interesting topics.</p>
<h3><strong>What did CodeBerry offer you? What was it like to study at our school?</strong></h3>
<p>The biggest advantage of CodeBerry is that it gives an overview of the whole process of web development, guiding you step by step through all the different stages. This helps you decide which part of it fits you most.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12255 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><strong>Do you have any experience, tips or tricks to share with those who are just starting their studies?</strong></h3>
<p>Web development has many different areas, it’s worth choosing a few to focus on, and just briefly know the others. If you ever need more, you can always learn it then.</p>
<h3><strong>What is the next step for you? What direction are you taking?</strong></h3>
<p>I would like to learn as much as possible and bring some of my own ideas to life. I’ve never let go of my agricultural knowledge, it will be exciting to see how it might come together with IT.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em><strong>In our <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/category/codeberry-student-stories/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">&#8220;CodeBerry Student Stories&#8221;</a> series we chat with our students who succeeded at finding a job as a developer.</strong></em></p>
<h3>Would you like to do the first steps on the way to become a sitebuilder?</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/a-brief-introduction-to-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">A Brief Introduction to Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/why-you-should-learn-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Why You Should Learn Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-much-can-you-make-as-a-programmer/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How much can you make as a programmer?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/how-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external"><strong>How to learn to code?</strong></a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/which-programming-language-is-right-for-you/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Which programming language is good for you?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-long-it-takes-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How Long It Takes to Learn to Code</a></li>
</ul>
<p><em><strong>Would you like to learn how to code? Come and try our<a href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external"> 25 first lessons for free at the CodeBerry Programming School</a>.</strong></em></p>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<h2></h2>
<h2 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ef5350;"><strong>Learn to code and change your career!</strong></span></h2>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 40px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12065" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>100% ONLINE</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12066" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-440x440.png 440w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4.png 512w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>IDEAL FOR BEGINNERS</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12067" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SUPPORTIVE COMMUNITY</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12068" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SELF-PACED LEARNING</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 10px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<h3 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #20c997;">Not sure if programming is for you? With CodeBerry you’ll like it.</span></h3>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 30px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-buttons aligncenter">
<div class="wp-block-button is-style-fill"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-white-color has-text-color has-background" style="border-radius: 10px; background-color: #ef5350;" href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><strong>TRY THE FIRST LESSONS FOR FREE</strong></a></div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 25px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12074" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png" sizes="(max-width: 282px) 100vw, 282px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png 564w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1-300x47.png 300w" alt="" width="282" height="45" /></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>From microwave ovens to web development—The story of Árpád Binecz</title>
		<link>/blog/en/web-development-story-of-arpad-binecz/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blog-admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 13:16:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[CodeBerry Student Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Árpád Binecz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bootstrap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Budapest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CodeBerry Programming School]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSS3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electrical engineering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HTML5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jQuery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SCSS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web development]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://codeberryschool.com/?p=5169</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Árpád Binecz (Bini) started as an embedded software engineer, worked at a startup, founded his own company and now, with a twist, he’s creating websites as a junior site builder. Enjoy our interview with one of our former students in the second episode of &#8220;CodeBerry Student Stories&#8221;. What was your job before you shifted to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Árpád Binecz</strong> (Bini) started as an embedded software engineer, worked at a startup, founded his own company and now, with a twist, he’s creating websites as a junior site builder. Enjoy our interview with one of our former students in the second episode of &#8220;<a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/category/codeberry-student-stories/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">CodeBerry Student Stories&#8221;.</a></p>
<h3><strong>What was your job before you shifted to web development?</strong></h3>
<p>I have a degree in electrical engineering. I worked as an embedded software engineer at an automotive company for four years. I also worked at a startup as well as starting my own leisure time managing company that I&#8217;ve since sold.</p>
<h3><strong>What does an embedded software engineer do?</strong></h3>
<p>An embedded software engineer develops circuits, not for computers, but rather for microwaves or cars. These circuits make things happen with a push of a button.</p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12254 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h3><strong>Did your original profession make studying any easier?</strong></h3>
<p>Quite a bit, e.g. in algorithmic thinking.</p>
<h3><strong>Why did you decide to switch to web development?</strong></h3>
<p>First of all, I was really interested in IoT (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_of_things" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">Internet of Things – ed.</a>) I knew the tools pretty well due to my original profession, but I had no idea how things would appear in a browser. I was curious. After all, I studied to become an engineer because I like understanding things. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>Secondly, I would like to continue entrepreneurship and this topic seems just right for that: by starting with some unique websites than creating a small digital agency. A lot of people did the same thing in my environment and it looks like an accomplishable and rather cool path to walk.</p>
<h3><strong>When you&#8217;re asked about your profession, how do you answer?</strong></h3>
<p>Depends on who’s asking — someone laic or a friend of mine from tech school. In the first case, I’m an IT newbie. Otherwise, a junior site builder.</p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12018 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h3>What does that mean? How does your typical day pass?</h3>
<p>We develop big IT systems at Apertus Kft.; I’m responsible for a small part of that. Keeping it simple: I receive ready designs and turn them into websites. I work on the looks, but for example, a clickable button is not my job.</p>
<p>To be a bit metaphoric, this is how I would describe the site builder profession: it’s a great jumpstart, with a kind of knowledge that sticks fast and makes it possible to stand with two feet on the quaggy ground of web technologies as well as the IT labor market.</p>
<h3><strong>Which languages do you use daily?</strong></h3>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/a-brief-introduction-to-web-development/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, and Bootstrap.</a> I also used JQuery once. As a site builder, I create the pieces that the lead developer then uses to complete the website.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-8527 size-large" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/computer-1245714_1920-1-1024x680.jpg" alt="Web development is an exciting and creative profession" width="1024" height="680" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/computer-1245714_1920-1-1024x680.jpg 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/computer-1245714_1920-1-300x199.jpg 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/computer-1245714_1920-1-768x510.jpg 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/computer-1245714_1920-1-1536x1020.jpg 1536w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/computer-1245714_1920-1-1080x717.jpg 1080w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/computer-1245714_1920-1.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<h3><strong>Do you enjoy your job? <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></strong></h3>
<p>Yes. My colleagues are fun. I’m just a little unsatisfied with myself because I feel I could do better and learn faster.</p>
<h3><strong>How long did you spend looking for a job?</strong></h3>
<p>I left my previous job in June, started studying in July, and was working by the beginning of September. I got an offer through friends.</p>
<h3><strong>Did you use anything else than CodeBerry for your studies?</strong></h3>
<p>No, only CodeBerry.</p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12255 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h3><strong>Can you give advice to newbies as a former student?</strong></h3>
<p>I think it’s worth having an overview of the whole field before choosing a technology and diving deep into that. It’s enough to know the smallest sellable unit thoroughly instead of knowing a little bit of everything.</p>
<p>For instance, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS and Bootstrap are a great combo. You can easily become a junior developer with those.</p>
<p><em><strong>In our <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/category/codeberry-student-stories/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">&#8220;CodeBerry Student Stories&#8221; series</a> we chat with our former students who succeeded at finding a job as a developer. If you want to know how, this topic is for you. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></strong></em></p>
<h3>Would you like to do the first steps on the way to become a sitebuilder?</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/a-brief-introduction-to-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">A Brief Introduction to Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/why-you-should-learn-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Why You Should Learn Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-much-can-you-make-as-a-programmer/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How much can you make as a programmer?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/how-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How to learn to code?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/which-programming-language-is-right-for-you/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Which programming language is good for you?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-long-it-takes-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How Long It Takes to Learn to Code</a></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Would you like to learn how to code, online? Come and <a href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">try our first 25 lessons for free</a> at the CodeBerry Programming School.</span></p>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<h2></h2>
<h2 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ef5350;"><strong>Learn to code and change your career!</strong></span></h2>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 40px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12065" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>100% ONLINE</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12066" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-440x440.png 440w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4.png 512w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>IDEAL FOR BEGINNERS</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12067" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SUPPORTIVE COMMUNITY</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12068" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SELF-PACED LEARNING</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 10px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<h3 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #20c997;">Not sure if programming is for you? With CodeBerry you’ll like it.</span></h3>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 30px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-buttons aligncenter">
<div class="wp-block-button is-style-fill"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-white-color has-text-color has-background" style="border-radius: 10px; background-color: #ef5350;" href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><strong>TRY THE FIRST LESSONS FOR FREE</strong></a></div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 25px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12074" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png" sizes="(max-width: 282px) 100vw, 282px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png 564w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1-300x47.png 300w" alt="" width="282" height="45" /></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>From high school programming to EPAM – The story of our student, Attila Blascsák</title>
		<link>/blog/en/from-high-school-programming-to-epam/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[blog-admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 03:44:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[CodeBerry Student Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CodeBerry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CSS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EPAM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epam blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epam careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epam coding challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epam coding questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epam coding test questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epam front end]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epam frontend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epam in english]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epam interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epam interview questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epam javascript interview questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epam meaning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epam mentor program]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epam programming questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epam python]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epam school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frontend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HTML]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Javascript]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Python]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[python for elementary students]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[python for high school students]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[python school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[python student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[student python]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web developer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://codeberryschool.com/?p=4740</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Attila Blascsák is one of CodeBerry’s first users, who successfully changed his career and became a web developer after studying with us. We had a chat with Attila about how he got here, what he learned about programming, and the difficulties of finding a job as a junior developer.  When someone asked about your profession [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;Attila Blascsák is one of CodeBerry’s first users, who successfully changed his career and became a web developer after studying with us. We had a chat with Attila about how he got here, what he learned and the difficulties of finding a job as a junior developer.&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:384,&quot;10&quot;:1,&quot;11&quot;:3}"><strong>Attila Blascsák</strong> is one of <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">CodeBerry</a>’s first users, who successfully changed his career and became a web developer after studying with us. We had a chat with Attila about how he got here, what he learned about programming, and the difficulties of finding a job as a junior developer. </span></p>
<h3><strong>When someone asked about your profession a few months ago, how did you answer? </strong></h3>
<p><span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;I used to say my job is networking at IT Services, meaning that I helped big companies join the internet. Our task spread from assuring the router arrived at the customer to actually making it work.&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:384,&quot;10&quot;:1,&quot;11&quot;:3}">I used to say my job is networking at <a href="https://www.it-services.hu/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">IT Services,</a> meaning that I helped big companies join the internet. Our task spread from assuring the router arrived at the customer to actually making it work. </span></p>
<h3><strong>And what is your answer now?</strong></h3>
<p><span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;I’m a frontend UI developer at EPAM. I work in a bigger team, developing an application relying mainly on frontend technologies and designing the user interface. I use HTML, CSS and JavaScript on a daily basis.&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:384,&quot;10&quot;:1,&quot;11&quot;:3}">I’m a frontend UI developer at <a href="https://www.epam.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external">EPAM</a>. I work in a bigger team, developing an application relying mainly on frontend technologies and designing the user interface.<a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/a-brief-introduction-to-web-development/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external"> I use HTML, CSS and JavaScript</a> on a daily basis. </span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12254 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h3><strong>That sounds great! So, programming wasn’t really a new task for you, was it? Did you encounter coding earlier?</strong></h3>
<p><span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;I’m a frontend UI developer at EPAM. I work in a bigger team, developing an application relying mainly on frontend technologies and designing the user interface. I use HTML, CSS and JavaScript on a daily basis.&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:384,&quot;10&quot;:1,&quot;11&quot;:3}">Yes, I actually started using HTML and CSS during elementary school. Later in high school, we used Python all the time, relying on an antique book. I had to quit doing it because the libraries cited by the author didn’t exist anymore, so the tasks were unsolvable. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></span></p>
<h3><strong>Where did the idea of web development come from? </strong></h3>
<p><span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;I’m a frontend UI developer at EPAM. I work in a bigger team, developing an application relying mainly on frontend technologies and designing the user interface. I use HTML, CSS and JavaScript on a daily basis.&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:384,&quot;10&quot;:1,&quot;11&quot;:3}">During my senior year of high school, two guys approached me, saying they needed web developers for their startup. Back then I had no clue about what I was about to dive into, but I said yes and I soon got the hang of it. Eventually, we finished the project, but web development had caught my attention, so I continued learning it on my own. Finally, I ran into a dead-end in spring, when I felt I can’t go on alone, I need a teacher. That’s when I found you. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> </span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12018 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Testimonial-1-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h3><strong>How long have you been studying with CodeBerry? </strong></h3>
<p><span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;I’m a frontend UI developer at EPAM. I work in a bigger team, developing an application relying mainly on frontend technologies and designing the user interface. I use HTML, CSS and JavaScript on a daily basis.&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:384,&quot;10&quot;:1,&quot;11&quot;:3}">Since June 2016. </span></p>
<h3><strong>And how did you like it, what were the advantages? </strong></h3>
<p><span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;I’m a frontend UI developer at EPAM. I work in a bigger team, developing an application relying mainly on frontend technologies and designing the user interface. I use HTML, CSS and JavaScript on a daily basis.&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:384,&quot;10&quot;:1,&quot;11&quot;:3}">To be honest, there wasn&#8217;t a tremendous amount of new information, but the course was great for recollecting my knowledge. The mentors helped me a lot – that was probably one of the best things in it. Having someone to discuss your problems with is a huge advantage. </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-8289" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/code-4918187_1920-1-1024x768.jpg" alt="You can learn programming online at Codeberry" width="1024" height="768" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/code-4918187_1920-1-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/code-4918187_1920-1-300x225.jpg 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/code-4918187_1920-1-768x576.jpg 768w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/code-4918187_1920-1-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/code-4918187_1920-1-1080x810.jpg 1080w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/code-4918187_1920-1.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>That’s good to hear. Now it’s the beginning of autumn, that means you’ve gained enough knowledge in 3 months to find a job.</p>
<h3><span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;I’m a frontend UI developer at EPAM. I work in a bigger team, developing an application relying mainly on frontend technologies and designing the user interface. I use HTML, CSS and JavaScript on a daily basis.&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:384,&quot;10&quot;:1,&quot;11&quot;:3}"><strong>How long did it take you to find one?</strong> (The interview took place in September 2016 – ed.) </span></h3>
<p><span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;I’m a frontend UI developer at EPAM. I work in a bigger team, developing an application relying mainly on frontend technologies and designing the user interface. I use HTML, CSS and JavaScript on a daily basis.&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:384,&quot;10&quot;:1,&quot;11&quot;:3}">Actually, I haven’t even decided to start looking for a job yet. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> </span><span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;I’m a frontend UI developer at EPAM. I work in a bigger team, developing an application relying mainly on frontend technologies and designing the user interface. I use HTML, CSS and JavaScript on a daily basis.&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:384,&quot;10&quot;:1,&quot;11&quot;:3}">I created a LinkedIn profile, where I stated I was studying to become a junior developer and added my new skills too. Two weeks later EPAM contacted me. I was going to create a portfolio before contemplating looking for a job, but EPAM was faster. They invited me to an interview right away. </span></p>
<h3><strong>I wanted to ask you if the search was difficult, but I guess we can skip this question. </strong></h3>
<p><span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;I’m a frontend UI developer at EPAM. I work in a bigger team, developing an application relying mainly on frontend technologies and designing the user interface. I use HTML, CSS and JavaScript on a daily basis.&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:384,&quot;10&quot;:1,&quot;11&quot;:3}">Yes. (Laughs) </span></p>
<p><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/all-access-self-paced" target="_blank" rel="noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-12255 size-full" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2.png" alt="" width="1024" height="340" srcset="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2.png 1024w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2-300x100.png 300w, /blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Self-paced-2-768x255.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a></p>
<h3><strong>What is the next step for you? What direction are you taking? </strong></h3>
<p><span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;I’m a frontend UI developer at EPAM. I work in a bigger team, developing an application relying mainly on frontend technologies and designing the user interface. I use HTML, CSS and JavaScript on a daily basis.&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:384,&quot;10&quot;:1,&quot;11&quot;:3}">React environment is my current favourite, I would like to learn more about it in the upcoming period. It’s also a huge dream of mine to teach programming in some form. Giving lectures or taking part in some more specific program, I don’t know yet, nor do I know how it’s going to happen, but I’m sure it will happen somehow. </span></p>
<h3><strong>As a well-experienced student, do you have any tips for those just starting to code? </strong></h3>
<p><span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;I’m a frontend UI developer at EPAM. I work in a bigger team, developing an application relying mainly on frontend technologies and designing the user interface. I use HTML, CSS and JavaScript on a daily basis.&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:384,&quot;10&quot;:1,&quot;11&quot;:3}">I think it’s important to understand that the learning process can’t really be accelerated. Programming is a big challenge, not easy in the beginning. But once you’ve got the hang of it and understand the logic, it all becomes clear. From that point onwards everything speeds up. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> </span></p>
<p><em><strong>In <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/category/interviews/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">“CodeBerry Success Stories”</a> series we talk with our students who have already changed their careers and now work as developers. If you’re curious what they did to accomplish that, stay tuned for the next episodes! </strong></em></p>
<h3>Would you like to do the first steps on the way to become a sitebuilder?</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/a-brief-introduction-to-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">A Brief Introduction to Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/why-you-should-learn-programming/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Why You Should Learn Programming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-much-can-you-make-as-a-programmer/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How much can you make as a programmer?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/en/how-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How to learn to code?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/which-programming-language-is-right-for-you/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">Which programming language is good for you?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/how-long-it-takes-to-learn-to-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">How Long It Takes to Learn to Code</a></li>
</ul>
<p><em><strong>Would you like to learn how to code? Come and try our first lessons for free at the <a href="https://codeberryschool.com/en/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external">CodeBerry Programming School</a>.</strong></em></p>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center" style="flex-basis: 100%;">
<h2></h2>
<h2 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #ef5350;"><strong>Learn to code and change your career!</strong></span></h2>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 40px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12065" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon1-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>100% ONLINE</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-thumbnail is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12066" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4-440x440.png 440w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon4.png 512w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>IDEAL FOR BEGINNERS</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-top">
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12067" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon3-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SUPPORTIVE COMMUNITY</strong></h4>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-top" style="flex-basis: 50%;">
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12068" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2.png 512w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-300x300.png 300w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-150x150.png 150w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/web_icon2-440x440.png 440w" alt="" width="200" height="200" /></figure>
</div>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SELF-PACED LEARNING</strong></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 10px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<h3 class="has-text-align-center"><span class="has-inline-color" style="color: #20c997;">Not sure if programming is for you? With CodeBerry you’ll like it.</span></h3>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 30px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-buttons aligncenter">
<div class="wp-block-button is-style-fill"><a class="wp-block-button__link has-white-color has-text-color has-background" style="border-radius: 10px; background-color: #ef5350;" href="https://orange.codeberryschool.com/auth/signup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener external" data-wpel-link="external"><strong>TRY THE FIRST LESSONS FOR FREE</strong></a></div>
</div>
<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 25px;" aria-hidden="true"></div>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-12074" src="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png" sizes="(max-width: 282px) 100vw, 282px" srcset="https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1.png 564w, https://codeberryschool.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/logo_green-1-300x47.png 300w" alt="" width="282" height="45" /></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
